T E A M
U P I
(http://club.tankfile.co.kr/upi)
Sub2smi by
UPI - 미르™
sync controled by
봄봄
(letmesleep@naver.com)
고맙소이다
몬타우크행 기차는
플랫폼 B...
[Man On P.A. ]
Montauk train on track "B. "
2004년
발렌타인데이에 관한 푸념들
[Man ]
Random thoughts
for Valentine's Day, 2004.
Today is a holiday invented
by greeting card companies...
오늘은 카드 회사가 만든 날로
[ Man On P.A. Continues ]
Last call--
사람들 기분을 엿 같이 만든다
to make people
feel like crap.
I ditched work today.
난 회사 땡땡이 치고
Took a train out to Montauk.
몬타우크행 기차를 탔다
[ Man On P.A. ]
Montauk train boarding
on track "B. "
I don 't know why.
영문을 모르겠다
Aah!
I'm not an impulsive person.
그다지 기분파도 아닌데
[ Panti ng ]
I guess Ijust woke up
in a funk this morning.
아침에 깰 때 찝찝했을 뿐
I gotta get my car fixed.
카센터에도 가야 하는데
H i. Ci ndy?
신디, 조엘이에요
I t's J oel. J oel!
Listen, I don't
feel very well today.
몸이 좀 안 좋아서요
식중독인가 봐요
No, food poisoning,
I think.
[Joel Continues ]
It's goddamn freezing on this beach.
바닷바람이라 무지 춥군
2월의 몬타우크에서, 조엘
Montauk in February.
Brilliant,Joel.
찢었나 보네
언제 그랬지?
Page is ripped out.
Don't remember doing that.
2년 만에 처음 쓰는 일기로군
It appears this is
my first entry in two years.
모래라기보단...
작은 돌멩이구먼
Sand is overrated.
It's just tiny little rocks.
누군가 만나고 싶은데
Ifonly I could
meet someone new.
그런 인연은 없을 성 싶다
I guess my chances ofthat happening
are somewhat diminished,
낯선 여자와 눈도 못 맞추니
seeing that I'm incapable
ofmaking eye contact
with a woman I don 't know.
Maybe I should
get back together with Naomi.
착한 나오미와
다시 만날지도 모르겠다
착한 거 좋잖아
She was nice.
Nice is good.
She loved me.
또 날 사랑했고
[ Woman Speaking, Faint ]
[ Chuckles Softly ]
왜 내가 사랑하게 되는 여자는
내게 관심도 없는 걸까
[Joel Continues ]
Why do I fall in love
with every woman I see...
who shows me
the least bit ofattention?
몬타우크
[ Train Horn Blows ]
H i.
- 안녕하세요
- 네?
- I just said hi.
- Hi. Hello. Hi.
- 안녕하냐고요
- 네, 안녕해요
가도 되죠?
Okay if I sit closer?
How far are you going?
- 어디까지 가요?
- 록빌 센터
Uh, Rockville Center.
Get out! Me too!
웬일이니!
나도인데
- 정말?
- 인연이네
Really?
What are the odds?
Do I knowyou?
나 본 적 있어요?
Doyou ever shop
at Barnes & Noble?
- 반즈 앤 노블 책방은?
- 갔었죠
Sure. Sure.
That's it!
거봐!
봤대도요
Yeah?
I've seen you, man!
Book slave there
for, like, five years now.
거기서 일한 지...
5년 된걸요
Ah. I would have thought
I would've remembered you.
Jesus! Is it fiveyears?
- 봤다면 기억할 텐데
- 머리 때문이에요
It might be the hair.
What might?
It changes a lot.
- 어떤?
- 염색했거든요
The color.
That's whyyou might not
recognize me.
완전 딴 사람 됐죠
It's called Blue Ruin,
the color.
Right. Yeah.
블루 루인이란 색인데
이름이 세련됐죠?
Snappy name, huh?
Ilike it.
좋네요
Yeah.
컬러들 명칭이
전부 세련됐어요
Anyway, this company
makes a whole line of colors
with equally snappy names.
Red-- Red Menace,
Yellow Fever,
Green Revolution.
레드 메너스, 옐로우 피버
그린 레볼루션
That'd be a job,
coming up with those names.
- 이름 짓는 것도 직업이겠죠
- 설마 그러려고요
You think there could
possibly be a job like that?
헤어 컬러라 봤자
50여 종일 텐데
I mean, how many hair colors
could there be? Fifty, maybe.
Someone's got that job.
누군가는 해야죠
'오렌지 빛 고엽제'
내가 만든 거예요
Agent Orange!
I came up with that one.
I apply my personality
in a paste.
- 난 변덕이 장난 아니죠
- 아닐 거 같은데요
Oh, I doubt that very much.
Well, you don't know me,
so...
날 모르잖아요
그러니 장담 못하지
you don't know, doyou?
Sorry. I was just--
I'm trying to be nice.
미안해요
좋게 말하려던 거뿐인데
Yeah. I got it.
네, 이해해요
[ Inhaling ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Sighs ]
- 난 클레멘타인이에요
- 조엘이에요
My name's Clementine,
by the way.
I'm Joel.
Hi,Joel.
Hey.
반가워요
Nojokes about my name.
이름 갖고 놀리기 없기!
Oh, no, you wouldn't do that.
You're trying to be nice.
그럴 리는 없겠다
착한 천사표니까
- 놀릴 게 있어야 놀리죠
- '넓고 넓은 바닷가에'
I don't know anyjokes
aboutyour name.
Huckleberry Hound.
I don't know what that means.
- 감도 안 오는데요
- 그렇게까지 해도?
Huckleberry Hound?
What areyou, nuts?
- 간첩이에요?
- 들켰네
It's been suggested.
[ Chuckles ]
♪ 내 사랑아, 내 사랑아
♪ 나의 사랑 클레멘타인
♪ Oh, my darlin', oh, my darlin'
Oh, my darlin' Clementine ♪
♪You were lost
and gone forever ♪
♪ 늙은 애비 혼자 두고
♪ 영영 어디 갔느냐
♪ Dreadful sorry
Clementine ♪♪
[Laughing]
No?
- 몰라요?
- 미안해요
I'm sorry.Just--
It's a pretty name, though.
It really is nice.
놀림 받는 건 안됐지만
예쁜 이름인걸요
어원이 인정 많단 뜻이죠?
It's, uh--
It means "merciful."
Right? Clemency?
Although it hardly fits.
이름은 그래도
나 순악질 여사예요
I'm a vindictive little bitch,
truth be told.
Gee, I-I wouldn't
think that aboutyou.
- 전혀 안 믿겨요
- 왜 안 믿길까?
Whywouldn'tyou
think that about me?
I don't know.
글쎄요, 그냥...
I just--
I don't know.
I just, uh--
착하게 보여서요
You seem nice, so--
Oh, now I'm nice?
나까지 착하다고요?
다른 말 없어요?
Oh, God. Don't you know
any other adjectives?
난 내가 착한 것도
남이 착하게 구는 것도 싫더라
I don't need "nice."
I don't need myselfto be it,
and I don't need anybody else to be it at me.
Okay.
[ Clementine ]
Joel?
조엘?
조엘 맞죠?
It's Joel, right?
Yes.
그래요
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
소리쳐서 미안해요
I'm a little out of sorts today.
기분이 영 꽝이라
[ Exhales ]
My embarrassing admission is,
이런 말 벙찌겠지만
그쪽, 착해서 좋아요
I really like
thatyou're nice right now.
I mean, I can't tell
from one moment to the next
what I'm gonna like,
내 변덕에 언제
발동 걸릴지 몰라도
but right now...
당장은...
착한 게 좋네요
I'm glad you are.
[ Giggles ]
I have so much stuff
that, uh, I probably should, uh--
할 일이 좀 있어서...
- 이것저것...
- 어머, 미안해요
Oh! I'm sorry. Okay.
I-I'm writing, and--
No, no. I just--
Sure. No. That's okay.
끄적댈 것이 좀...
I just have--
You know, this is--
Okay.
- Ohh! Hey!
- Take care, then.
- 이봐요
- 잘 가요
Jesus!
♪♪ [ Radio: Pop ]
Hi. I could, uh,
give you a ride, ifyou need.
웬만하면 타고 가요
It's cold.
- 추운데
- 마다 않죠, 얼어 죽겠는데
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah?
It is frosty.
You're not a stalker
or anything, right?
I'm not a stalker.
- 스토커 아니죠?
- 스토커라니
You're the one that talked to me.
Remember?
자기가 말 걸어 놓곤
지침서에 나온 낡은 수법이에요
That is the oldest trick
in the stalker book.
스토커 지침서란 게 있다고요?
Really?
There's a stalker book?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I gotta read that one.
한번 읽어봐야겠네
Look, I'm sorry if I came off
sorta nutso. I'm not, really.
살짝 간 애처럼 굴어서
미안해요
Oh, it's okay.
I didn't thinkyou were.
괜찮아요, 그 정도는 아니에요
Did you wanna have a drink?
한 잔 할래요?
있는 건 술 뿐이라...
I have lots of drinks,
and I could, um--
Um--
[ Chuckles ]
Never mind.
됐어요, 되게 뻘쭘하네
잘 가요
Sorry. That was stupid.
I'm embarrassed now.
No, no, no, no.
Good night,Joel.
블루 루인 두 잔!
Two Blue Ruins.
Thankyou.
- 땡큐
- 쭉 들이켜요
Drink up, young man.
It'll make
the whole seduction part
less repugnant.
알딸딸해져야
어떻게 찔러보지
I'm just kidding!
농담이에요
쫄긴!
[ Laughs ]
Come on.
[ Exhales ]
- 입에 지퍼를 채웠네
- 미안해요
You're kinda closed-mouthed,
aren'tyou?
[Whispers ]
I'm sorry.
워낙 맹숭하게 사는 터라
It's just, you know,
my life isn't that interesting.
I go to work, I come home.
직장 아니면 집이라
얘깃거리도 없어요
Don't know what to say.
You should read myjournal.
일기장만 봐도 완전히...
I mean, it's just... blank.
무미건조하죠
그럼 속상하거나
초조하지 않나?
Really?
Does that makeyou
sad oranxious?
I mean, I'm always anxious,
thinking I'm not living
my life to the fullest,
난 잘 살고 싶어서 조바심 나던데
taking advantage
of every possibility,
누릴 건 다 누리고
1분 1초도 낭비하지 않고
making sure
I'm not wasting one second
ofthe little time I have.
생각은 하죠
I think about that.
Yeah?
[ Both Laughing ]
정말 착하다!
이 말이 절로 나오네
You're really nice.
Ohh!
God, I have to
stop saying that.
I'm gonna marryyou.
우리 결혼할 거야
확실해요
Iknowit.
[Slurps Drink]
Um... okay.
그렇군요
Joel, you should come up
to the Charles with me sometime.
언젠간 나와 찰스강에 갈 거야
It gets frozen this time ofyear.
이맘때는 꽁꽁 어는데
That sounds scary.
Exactly.
- 으스스하네
- 그러니까
우리 소풍 가요
I'll pack a picnic.
A night picnic.
Night picnics are different.
밤 소풍은 색다른 묘미가 있죠
And, um, we could--
Sounds good.
재미있겠네
- 근데 이제 가봐야 돼요
- 가지 말아요
But I-- I should, uh, go.
Now.
You should stay.
아침에 일찍 일어나야 돼서...
No, I really-- I'm-- I--
I have to get up so early.
그럼 전화 줘요
그래 줄 거죠?
I would likeyou
to call me.
Would you do that?
I would like it.
좋아요
Yes.
Wish me a happyValentine's Day
when you call!
전화로 발렌타인데이
축하해줘요
That'd be nice.
꼭 듣고 싶어
[ Beeping ]
[ Line Ringing ]
- 왜 이제 해요?
- 막 들어왔어요
[ Clementine]
What tookyou so long?
I justwalked in.
- 나 보고 싶어요?
- 이상하게 그렇네
Mm-hmm. You miss me?
Yeah.
Oddly enough, I do.
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
- 거 봐요, 나하고 결혼한대도
- 그러게
You said "I do."
I guess that means were married.
[ Laughs ]
I guess so.
내일 밤 허니문 가기에요?
Tomorrow night?
Honeymoon on ice?
It's really solid
this time ofyear.
꽝꽝 얼었으니 걱정 마요
Whoa! I don't know.
- 어째 불안한데
- 얼른 와요, 어서 오래도
Come on.
Eee!
Come on, come on.
[ Sighs ]
Whew.
Oh. So beautiful.
눈이 부시네!
[Clementine ]
Isn't it?
그렇죠?
[ Sighs ]
[ Giggling ]
Uh, don't go too far.
멀리 가지 마요
- Whoo! Oww! Ow!
- Whoa! Oh!
괜찮아요?
- Are you okay?
- Ouch! Fuck it.
궁둥이 아파 죽겠네!
Ohh! Oh, myass!
[ Grunts ]
I think I should go back.
Come on. Come on!
- 이만 나가요
- 어서요
- 왜요?
- 깨지면 어떡해!
What if it breaks?
지금 그런 생각이 들까?
냉큼 이리 와요
- "What if"?.
Do you really care right now?
- Huh?
Come here. Please.
[ Whispers ]
Come on.
[ Mutters ]
Ohh.
Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Slidy-slidy.
Whoa! [ Chuckles ]
미끌미끌!
This is good.
Here, let me show you
this one thing.
- 은근히 재미있네
- 뭐 보여줄게요
What areyou doing?
Whoa.
- 뭐하게?
- 누워요
[ Sighs ]
Come on.
어서요
Think I heard a crack.
- 금 갈 텐데
- 금 안 가요
[ Laughing ]
It's not gonna crack
or break or--
깨지지도 않고
It's so thick.
Show me which constellations
you know.
별자리 알려줘요
Um-- Oh.
하나도... 모르는데
I don't... know any.
Show me
which ones you know.
- 하나라도 있겠지
- 알았어요
Okay.
어디 보자...
Oh. Here's Osidius.
- '오시디어스'네
- 어디?
Where?
저기, 보여요?
Right there.
See?
호를 그리면서
십자모양을 했잖아요
Sort of a swoop
and a cross.
Osidius the Emphatic.
[ Laughs ]
- 순 뻥이죠?
- 아니, 저거잖아요
You're full of shit.
Right?
Nope.
Osidius is right there.
Swoop and cross.
- 호에 십자형!
- 그만 놀려라!
[ Laughing ]
Shut the fuck up!
[ Whispers ]
Clementine.
클레멘타인...
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
그만 일어나요
Hey.
이런
Sorry to wakeyou,
but we're... here.
깨워서 미안한데
다 왔어요
[ Sighs ]
Ahh.
Can I come over
to your house...
그쪽 집에 가도 돼요?
to sleep?
자고 싶은데 너무 피곤해요
I'm so tired.
[ Sighs ]
Okay. Um, yeah. Sure.
그러죠, 뭐
Let me get my toothbrush.
Yeah. Oh.
칫솔 갖고 올게요
Just--
Yes?
- 네?
- 괜찮아요?
Can I helpyou?
What doyou mean?
무슨...?
Can I helpyou with something?
[ Sniffles ]
뭐 도와줄까요?
No.
아뇨
What areyou doing here?
여긴 어떻게...?
무슨 영문인지 모르겠군요
I'm not really sure
whatyou're asking me.
Oh.
Thanks.
알았어요
♪ I needyourlovin'♪
♪ Like thesunshine♪
짐 캐리
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
케이트 윈슬렛
커스틴 던스트
이터널 선샤인
(Eternal Sunshine. 2004)
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪♪
♪♪ [ Stops ]
각본 : 찰리 카우프만
- 159번 집이야
- 뭐라고?
[ Man # 1 ]
We're looking for 1 59.
[ Man #2 ] What number's that?
[ Man # 1 ]
I don't know where that is.
어딘지 잘 모르겠군
감독 : 미셸 공드리
젠장, 불이라도 좀 켜놓든지
Jesus Christ, you'd think
they'd light the number,
or at least put a number on--
[ Man #2 ]
Is that him?
[ Man # 1 ] I think so.
- 저 치야?
- 아마도
Yeah, that's hi m.
Wait. That's him.
맞네
[ Giggling]
- 조엘
- 프랭크
Hey,Joel.
Frank.
Oh, shit.
기막혀!
Jesus. The only
Valentine's Day cards I get
are from my mother.
달랑 한 장 온 카드가
엄마가 보낸 거라니
비참하다
How pathetic is that, huh?
You're lucky
you have Clementine, man.
클레멘타인 진짜 쿨하더라
She is way cool.
발렌타인데이 맞이
계획이라도?
Hey, you got any big
Valentine's Day plans with her?
라쿠나 회사
No.
없어
하루 전인데 예약 안 하면
햄버거로 때우게 돼
Well, it's only a day away.
Better make some reservations
or something.
Don't want to end up
at Mickey D's. Right?
[ Chuckling ]
McRomance!
일명 러브버거!
You want some fries
with that shake?
- 감자튀김도 하실라우?
- 나 그만 가서 자야 돼
I have to, uh,
go to sleep now, Frank.
It's 8:30.
8시 반인데
♪♪[Man #1 Singing, Falsetto ]
[Man #2 ]
Patrick, stop it.
패트릭, 그만해
[ Sighs ]
Ohh! Okay.
큰일날 뻔 했네
Okay. Okay.
Whew. Okay.
슬슬 시작하자
[Man #1 ]
Showtime at the Apollo.
Shh, shh, shh. Hey.
[ Whispers ]
Quiet.
조용!
[ Grunting ]
그거 좀 벗어
[Equipment Dropping Onto Floor]
- 조엘이구나
- 프랭크
[Frank ]
Hey,Joel. What's up?
[Joel]
Oh. Hi, Frank.
[ Mailbox Door
Opening, Closing]
[ Keys Jingling]
[ Sighs ]
I only get Valentine's Day cards
from my mom.
달랑 한 장 온 카드가
엄마가 보낸 거라니
How pathetic is that?
[ Man's Voice Echoing,
Indistinct ]
비참하다
클레멘타인 진짜 쿨하더라
You're I ucky
you have Clementine, Joel.
Hey, you got, uh, any, uh, big
Valentine's Day plans with her?
발렌타인데이 맞이
계획이라도?
[ Whispers ]
No.
없어
It's only a day away.
하루 전인데 예약 안 하면
햄버거로 때우게 돼
Better make a reservation
or something.
Don't wanna end up
at Mickey D's.
일명 러브버거!
[ Chuckling ]
[Woman ]
Oh, no!
저런
발렌타인데이 사흘 전이라
화해하려고 내가 총대를 맸지
[Joel] Yes! Valentine's Day
is three goddamn days away!
I want it resolved.
I'm willing to be
the one to resolve it.
근데 전화했더니
번호를 바꿨더군
So I cal I her,
and she's changed her num ber.
그래서 선물부터 사러 갔어
[Joel]
So I walked over to Antic Attic,
you know, to get her something.
I thought I'd go over to work,
give her an early valentine, and--
좀 이른 발렌타인데이
선물을 주려고
근데...
어땠는지 알아?
You won't bel ieve it.
She's there with...
어떤 영계 하나 끼고선
this guy,
this really young guy.
날 난생 처음 보는 사람처럼 굴더라고
And she looks at me like
she doesn't even know who I am.
Excuse me?
찾으시는 책이라도 있으세요?
Can I help you
find something, sir?
[ Chuckles ]
- 클레멘타인
- 패트릭, 우리 자기 왔네
Hey, Clem-ato.
Patrick! Baby boy.
Whatyou doing here, baby?
[Patrick ]
Just came to surpriseyou.
- 웬일이래?
- 너 놀래주려고
Let me know
ifyou need something, sir.
You look good.
언제든 말씀하세요
- 좋아라
- 일은?
- [ Patrick ] Hi.
- [ Kiss ]
How are you?
[ Clementine ] Pretty good.
Pretty bored. Pretty tired.
왕 따분하고 왕 피곤해
[ Patrick ]
Uh-huh.
- 자기하고 눕고 싶다
- 좋지
[ Clementine ]
I so want what's in your suit.
Oh, good.
[ Panti ng ]
왜...
Why?
Why would she do that to me?
[ Sighs ]
I'm sorry.
나한테 왜 이럴까
Hey, does anybody want a joint?
- 한 대 피울래?
- 롭, 그러지 좀 마
Oh, God, Rob, give it a rest.
Oh, God.
She's punishing me.
너무 솔직하다고
벌주는 걸 거야
I know, honey.
For being honest.
It's horrible.
I should just go to her house.
- 집에 가볼까 봐
- 가면 안 돼
No! No, no, no.
You don't wanna go there, man.
You don't wanna go there.
Get off. It's too--
- 그건 너무...
- 하긴, 너무 비굴하지
Right.
Yeah.
I don't want to seem desperate.
완전히 끝내자는 신호로 여겨
Joel, why don't you just see this as a sign,
make a clean break. Right?
그렇지?
Right?
[Joel Groans ]
까짓 거 톡 까놓고 말해줄게
All right,Joel,
look, man, seriously.
[ Woman ]
Rob!
Here's the deal.
하지 마, 뭘 하려고?
Don't do that.
Rob, what are you doing?
No, no, no, no.
그럼 무슨 뾰족한 수라도 있어?
What's your fucking suggestion, Carrie?
What's your brilliant, reasoned solution?
이러다 우리가 싸우겠다
You're gonna make this
about our shit now?
This isn't about us.
내 말이!
조엘은 애가 아냐
Iagree. It's not about us.
It's aboutJoel, who's an adult.
Okay?
싸고돌지 말라고
Not Mama Carrie's kid.
- What areyou--
- That's your laundry!
네 빨래는 네가 해!
차라리 잘됐네
그랬군
That's great.
That's good.
[ Dog Barks ]
Okay.
이거야
클레멘타인이 조엘을
기억에서 삭제했으니
그녀에게 둘의 관계를
언급 말 것, 라쿠나 사
What is it?
[ Rob ] I don't know.
It's some place that does a thing.
- 뭐야?!
- 그런 일을 하는 곳인가 봐
라쿠나
[ Woman ]
Good morning. Lacuna.
라쿠나 사입니다
No, I'm sorry.
That offer expired
after the newyear.
죄송한데 새해부턴
그 일을 안 해요
네, 어디 보자...
Yeah, sure.
We can fit you i n--
How about on the fifth?
5일은 어떠세요?
수요일이요
성함이...?
That's a Wednesday.
All right, great.
Couldyou spell that, please?
낮에 연락되는 전화번호도
Okay, and we'll need
a daytime phone number.
Great. Have a nice day.
See you then.
그럼 그 때 뵐게요
May I hel p you?
어떻게 오셨죠?
- 전 조엘 배리쉬인데...
- 네?
I 'm J oel Barish.
Excuse me?
I 'm Joel. Barish.
I have an appointment with Dr.--
조엘 배리쉬인데
박사님 성함이...
Mierzwiak.
'하워드 미어즈왝'
작성해주세요
- Here. Could you please fill this out?
- I just want to talk to him.
- 얘기만 할 건데
- 그래도 하셔야 해요
You still need to
fill the form out, sir.
Really?
- Thankyou.
- [ Mutters ] Great.
고맙습니다
I don't have a pen.
- 펜이 없는데
- 거기 있어요
There's a pen right there.
[Phone Rings ]
Goodmorning. Lacuna.
Oh.
라쿠나 사입니다
Oh,yeah, that offer. That's done now.
That expired after the newyear.
새해부턴 그 일을 안 하는데요
Mr. Barish?
배리쉬 씨?
- 기분은 어떠세요?
- 사실 별로예요
How are we today?
Not too good, actually.
- 깜짝이야!
- 미안, 난...
Boo!
Oh, my God! Stan!
Sorry.
Sorry, I was just--
I'm working!
일하잖아
[ Mutters ]
Sorry. Sorry.
- 여기요
- 고마워
[ Whispers ]
Here, Doctor.
Thankyou.
You should not
have seen this.
보면 안 되는 건데
죄송하게 됐습니다
I apologize.
This is a hoax, right?
I mean, this is Clem--
이거 장난이죠?
그 애가...
- 절대 아닙니다
- 아니에요
I assureyou, no.
[Woman ]
No.
Mm-mmm.
There's no such thing as this.
이건 말도 안 돼요
파일은 극비라
보여드릴 수는 없고
Look, our files are confidential,
Mr. Barish,
so I can't showyou evidence.
크루친스키 양은 힘들어하면서
Suffice it to say that Miss, uh--
Miss Kruczynski was not happy,
and she wanted to move on.
다 잊고 싶어하길래
그렇게 한 겁니다
[Dr. Mierzwiak]
We provide that possibility.
"Miss Kruczynski was not happy
and wanted to move on.
[Banging]
힘들어하면서
다 잊고 싶어했다!
We provide
that possibility."
그래서 그렇게 해준 거다!
이게 말이 돼?
What the hell is that?
Nicest guy
she everwent out with.
착해서 좋다고 할 땐 언제고!
젠장!
[Rob ]
Oww! Fuck!
God, Rob! Give it a rest!
롭, 웬만큼 해 둬
It's okay.
It's all right.
- 그냥 놔둬
- 새장 만들잖아
Carrie, I am making
a birdhouse.
What can Isay,Joel?
You know Clementine. She's like that.
원래 그런 애려니 해
좀 욱하잖아
She's impulsive.
She decided to erase you
almost as a lark.
재미 삼아 해본 거겠지
[ Sighs ]
A lark.
재미 삼아?
왜, 왜, 왜!
왜 그런 건데!
[ Sobbing ]
Why? Why? Why?
Why did you do that?
잠깐만요!
막무가내로 들어오네요
[Woman ]
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
I'm sorry, Doctor.
He just barged right in here.
- 당장 해줘요
- 발렌타인데이 전날이라...
Okay. I want it done.
I told him pre-Valentine's Day
is our busy time.
괜찮아, 매리
- Oh, th-th-that's-- that's okay, Mary.
- But there are people waiting.
- 다들 기다리는데
- 안으로 들어오시죠
Mr. Barish, ifyou'd like to, uh--
to come inside.
이 부인 좀 모셔줘
살펴가세요
And, Mary, ifyou could take care of Mrs. Woo.
Good-bye, Mrs. Woo.
Yes, ofcourse.
이제...
Now, the, uh--
the first thing
we need you to do, Mr. Barish,
가장 먼저 하셔야 할 일은
is to go home...
클레멘타인과 관계된 건
모조리 모아오는 겁니다
and collect everythingyou own
that has some association with Clementine.
Anything.
전부 다요
And we'll use these items to create
a map ofClementine in your brain.
그걸 이용해서 선생 머릿속에
그녀의 기억회로를 만드는 거죠
Okay?
사진부터 해서
옷, 선물도 그렇고
So we'll need, uh,
uh, photos, clothing, gifts,
그 분께 받은 책도 챙기세요
둘이 산 CD나
books she may have bought you,
CDs you may have bought together,
일기장도요
journal entries.
집안을 정리하며
We want to emptyyour home--
We want to emptyyour I ife
ofClementine.
클레멘타인도 털어버리세요
구성된 기억회로에 따라
오늘 밤 삭제에 들어갑니다
And after the mapping is done,
our technicians will do the erasing
in your home tonight.
그러고 나면
아침에 일어나서부터는
That way, when you awake
in the morning,
you'll findyourselfin your own bed
as ifnothing had happened--
새로운 삶이
선생을 맞을 거예요
a new life awaitingyou.
[ Ti res Screech ]
[ Driver ]
Wake up, buddy!
정신이 있어 없어!
[ Mary]
No, I'm sorry, Mrs. Sobel.
죄송한데 한 달에
세 번은 못합니다
You can't have the procedure done
three times in one month.
Wel l, it's just not our policy--
How are you today, Mr. Barish?
방침이 그래요
오셨어요?
네, 여기 있어요
Hello. I'm right here.
급하시다니까
3월 1일에 오셔서
I know it's an emergency,
and we'll do everything we can--
We can fit you in on the first of March.
Maybeyou could talk to the doctor,
a-and he--
상담부터 받고
All right, so let's make an appointment.
What day wouldyou like
to come in this week?
그럼 이번 주 언제가 좋으세요?
- 배리쉬 씨!
- 오후에는 꽉 차 있어요
Mr. Barish.
U m, he's real ly busy
this afternoon.
Maybe tomorrow would be better.
Around 12:15? Can you do that?
내일 12시 15분은 어떠세요?
발렌타인데이 때문에
2월은 좀 바빠요
February is very busy for us
because ofValentine's Day.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Knocks ]
♪♪ [DixielandJazz]
This is, uh, Stan Fink,
스탠이라고 베테랑 기술자죠
one ofourmost experienced
andskilled technicians.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
- 오늘 밤 맡아서 처리해줄 겁니다
- 반갑습니다
He'll be handling
your case tonight.
Great to meet you,
Mr. Barish.
전 조엘 배리쉬라고
My name is Joel Barish,
and I'm here to erase
Clementine Kruczynski.
클레멘타인의 기억을
지우려고 왔습니다
이제 클레멘타인에 대해
말씀해보시죠
Very good.
Now, tell me about, uh, Clementine.
Uh, I was...
전 나오미란 여자와
Iiving with this woman, Naomi,
동거를 했어요
2년 전에요
uh, a coupleyears ago,
그때 친구네 부부가
바닷가로 초대를 했는데
and my friends Rob and Carrie
invited us to this party at the beach--
I don't like parties.
나오미가 못 간다고 해서
저 혼자 갔죠
Naomi couldn't go, but I went...
and I, uh, met Clementine.
거기서 클레멘타인을 만났어요
[Pencils Clattering On Floor]
I 'm sorry.
죄송해요
최근 기억부터
거꾸로 지워나갈 겁니다
Let's start with
your most recent memories...
and work backwards from there,
more or less.
There's an emotional core...
기억엔 감정의 중심부가 있는데
to each of our memories,
그 부분을 없앨 때
기억 말소가 오고
and when you eradicate that core
it starts its degradation process.
By the timeyou wake up
in the morning,
아침에 일어나면
타깃으로 삼은 기억들은
all the memories we've targeted
will have withered and disappeared,
as in a dream upon waking.
꿈처럼 희미해지거나
사라질 거예요
Is there any risk
ofbrain damage?
뇌가 손상될 수도 있나요?
이 과정 자체가
뇌 손상인 겁니다
Well, uh, technically speaking,
the procedure is brain damage,
하지만 과음한 날 정도의
충격만 주는 거죠
but it's on a parwith
a night ofheavy drinking.
Nothing you'll miss.
편하세요?
Comfortable?
지워 나갈 기억의 회로를
만들 겁니다
Whatwe're doing here, Mr. Barish,
is actually creating a map ofyour brain.
[Mierzwiak]
Okay, let's getstarted.
시작하세, 오늘 밤 손보려면
지금 해 둬야지
Ifwe want to get
this procedure underwaytonight,
we have some work to do.
물건에 대해 반응해주세요
I want you to react
to these objects, Mr. Barish,
ifyou will.
[ Clementine Whooping, Laughing]
There's a good story
behind this one--
- 거기 얽힌 사연은...
- 그냥 생각만 하는 게
Uh, actually, Mr. Barish,
I'll get a much better
emotional readout...
감정이 더 정확히 읽혀요
ifyou refrain from any sort of
verbal description ofthe items.
- 기억에 집중만 하세요
- 죄송해요
Just try to focus on the memories.
Oh. Sorry. Okay.
왕성한 활동을 보이는데요
[Stan ]
Healthyactivityup there again.
Healthyreadouts. Very good.
좋았어, 다른 물건입니다
- Here's another object.
- [ Clementine's Voice ]
That's so--
다음!
Next item. Okay.
여기요
Potato head.
[ Chuckles ]
감자인형이라...
다음!
- Next item. Okay.
- [ Electronic Crackling]
[Stan, Voice Electronically Processed]
Just focus on the memories.
Patrick, do me a favor.
- 기억에 집중하세요
- 나 좀 도와줄래?
[ Stan ] Hey, Patrick,
do me a favor, willya?
[ Patrick ] Yeah.
나 좀 도와줄래?
전압조절기 좀 봐줘
[ Stan ]
Can you check the voltage regulator?
What do we got there?
U h, voltage looks fi ne.
Real ly?
- 전압은 정상인데
- 그래?
Wel l, I 'm not wi pi ng
as clean as I like here.
I 'm-- [ Scoffs ]
근데 시원하게 삭제되질 않아
[ Mierzwiak's Voice, Distant ]
Well, uh, technically the procedure
is brain damage.
이 과정 자체가
뇌 손상인 겁니다
Check the, uh--
Check the connections, please.
접속 좀 확인해봐
Oh, there you are.
I --
여기 계셨군요
Why am I --
I don't understand
what I'm looking at.
대체...
저게 어떻게 된 거죠?
전 여기 있는데, 어떻게...
'데자부'로군요!
Why am I
standing here and--
Oh, my God.
Deja vu.
- 이건 참...
- 시작하세
Deja vu.
This is so--
All right, we should get started.
Ifwe're gonna get the procedure...
- 오늘밤 손보려면 지금 해 둬야지
[ Simultaneously]
underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
내 머릿속에 들어왔군요
[ Whispering ]
I'm in my head already,
aren't I?
그럴 겁니다
그렇게 보이네요
I suppose so.
Uh, this is about right.
This is what it--
This is what itwould look like.
아주 좋아요
Very good.
끝나고 물건을 없애야만
[ Simultaneously]
We'll dispose ofthese mementos
when we're done here.
Thatwayyou won't be confused later
by their unexplainable presence in your home.
어디서 난 건가 하는
불상사를 막죠
[ Stan ]
Ah, there we go.
Patrick?
Yeah?
- 패트릭?
- 응
[Stan's Voice, Echoing]
Patrick, canyou check--
Patrick?
- 패트릭...
- 패트릭?
I'm gettingsome sort ofreadout
ofmy own voice.
Patrick? Patrick?
- 웬 전선이 이렇게 많아?
- 장비가 많으니까
- Why are there so many wires?
- [Stan ]A lot ofequipment.
- Does that help?
-[Stan ]Areyou sure
you set that thing up properly?
- 됐어?
- 제대로 연결한 거 맞아?
[Patrick ] How's that?
[Mary] How areyou today,
Mr. Barish?
- 기분은 어떠세요?
- 여기요
There we are,
Mr. Barish.
[Stan's Voice ] That's better.
- I don't know if I like this.
- Think I might try this, then.
- 이래도 될지...
- 이렇게 해보지
We're almost done now.
- 거의 됐어
- 일기장이 한 몫 할 겁니다
Mmm.Journal.
That would be invaluable.
[Stan's Voice, ElectronicallyAccelerated]
"I met someone tonight.
I don't know what to do.
'누굴 만났는데
어쩌면 좋을까'
'클레멘타인이라는
멋진 여자다'
Her name is Clementine,
and she's amazing. "
- [ Scream i ng ]
- Whoa! J esus!
맙소사!
- 왜?
- 조심 좀 해
What? What?
Come on! Careful!
Step back!
Just take it easy.
진정하라고
[ Beeps ]
That's fine.
- 멀쩡하구먼
- 일내지 말자
Let's not roach the guy.
[ Sighs ]
All right, you got that one.
하나 건졌어
This place is sort of a dump,
don't you think?
It's an apartment, Patrick.
- 쓰레기장이 따로 없네
- 아파트잖아, 패트릭
[ Whispers ]
Patrick.
패트릭...
쓰레기장까진 아니고
좀 후진 정도지
Well, not a dump, then,
but sorta plain. Uninspired.
And there's sort of
a stale smell.
퀴퀴한 냄새도 나
Patrick, can wejust please
get through this?
일 좀 하면 안 될까?
할 일이 태산이야
We got a very long night
ahead of us. Come on.
Yeah. Yeah.
- 알았어
- 어서
[ Door Unlocking, Opening]
[Joel Whispering]
This is the last time I sawyou.
널 마지막으로 본 때로군
[Joel Clears Throat, Sighs ]
[ Heavy Sigh ]
I t's 3:00.
- 새벽 3시야
- 있잖아
I kinda sorta wreckedyour car.
내가 자기 차 뽀갰어
[ Sighs ]
Were you driving drunk?
음주 운전했군
기막혀!
It's pathetic.
I was a little tipsy.
좀 취한 거 갖고
뭘 기막히기까지 하냐?
Don't call me pathetic.
기막히지
사람 죽일 수도 있는 짓을 한 거야
Wel l, it is pathetic.
I t's fucki ng i rresponsible.
Could've killed somebody.
[Sighs ] Oh, God.
죽였는지도 모르니
뉴스라도 볼까?
Maybe you did kill somebody.
Should we turn on the news and see?
Oh, Christ!
Should I check the grill to see
ifthere's any children or small animals?
I didn't kill anybody!
아니면 사고 낸 흔적 있나
차에 가 봐?
It's just a fucking dent, Joel.
You're like an old lady or something.
잔소리 수준이 아줌마야
그러는 넌?
고주망태고?
Well, what are you like?
A wino?
뭐 그런 올드한 표현을
다 쓰냐?
[ Laughing ]
Jesus, areyou from the '50s
or something?
A wino?
Face it,Joely.
솔직히 말해
늦게 와서 뚜껑 열린다고
You're freaked out because
I was out late withoutyou,
우리의 밴댕이 씨께선
궁금해 돌아가시겠지
and in your little wormy brain...
you're trying to figure out,
did she fuck someone tonight?
'저게 누구하고 뒹굴고 왔나?'
내 보기엔 너 뒹굴다 왔어
No, see, Clem,
I assume
you fucked someone tonight.
Isn't that howyou get people
to likeyou?
친해지려면 자고 보잖아
[Sighs ]
I'm sorry. Okay?
미안해, 진심이 아냐
Clem, I didn't mean it.
All right?
Clem?
Yourkeys.
열쇠 여기 있어
이젠 필요 없어
I was just-- I was just--
[ Sighs ]
I won't need them anymore.
화나고 속상해서
내뱉은 말이야
Angry or annoyed or something,
I don't know.
[DoorSlams ]
Clem?
클레멘타인?
[ ComputerBeeps ]
[Stan ]
Got it.
됐다!
Mary's coming over tonight.
매리도 온대
희소식이지?
[Patrick]
Yeah?
Yeah.
Just thoughtyou'd wanna know.
오는 건 반가운데
날 안 좋아하는 거 같아
[Patrick ]
I like Mary. I like when she comes to visit.
Ijust don't think she likes me.
She likes you okay.
괜한 소리!
Maybe I should invite my girlfriend over.
I have a girlfriend now.
그럼 내 여자친구도 불러야겠다
Do whateveryou want.
Did I tell you I have--
- 맘대로 해
- 내가 말했나?
[ Clicks Tongue ]
Yeah.
[Keyboard Typing]
Did I tell you
I have a new girlfriend?
- 여자친구 생긴 거 말했나?
- 일에 집중하자
We gotta focus here,
Patrick.
Yeah, the thing is,
실은 상황이 좀...
our situation is--
is a little weird.
- 엽기야, 여자친구 일 말이야
- 어련하겠냐
My girlfriend situation.
I'm sure it is.
[ Laughs ]
You gotta be--
어떻게...
[ Engine Starts ]
Clem, let me driveyou home.
- 집에 데려다 줄게
- 꺼져, 이 나쁜 놈아!
Get out ofmyface, faggot!
주위를 봐
산산조각 나고 있어
Look at it out here!
It's all falling apart!
I'm erasing you, and I'm happy!
네가 그랬듯 널 지우며
행복해하고 있다고
You did it to me first!
네가 먼저 시작했잖아
어떻게 그럴 수 있어!
I can't believe
you did this to me.
Goddamn it.
Clem! Can you hear me?
내 말 들려?
By morning you'll be gone!
아침이면 넌 사라져!
같잖은 러브스토리에
딱 맞는 결말이지!
The perfect ending
to this piece-of-shit story!
[ Engine Knocking ]
[Patrick] Is there something wrong
with a girl being attracted to me?
Is that a problem?
나 좋아하면
문제 있는 여자야?
아니, 그냥 웃겨서
[Stan ]
No, I think it's... funny.
[ Patrick ]
So, who do you think's better-looking,
me or this guy?
이 남자하고 나하고
누가 더 잘생겼어?
패트릭, 일하자
[ Stan ]
Patrick, let's focus, buddy.
[ Patrick ]
Remember that girl
we did last week?
지난 주에 기억 지웠던...
The one with the... potatoes?
감자인형 갖고 있던 여자
[ Stan ]
That girl?
That's this guy's girl.
- 그 여자가?
- 그 여자가 이 남자 여자친구야
[ Patrick ]
Right.
[ Stan ] Yeah.
이젠 아니지
우리가 해결했으니까
[ Stan Chuckling ]
Was. We took care ofthat.
Oh, God!
Well, uh...
I ki nda fel I i n love with her
that night.
그 여자한테 뿅 갔어
[ Laughing ]
What? You little fuck--
- 뭐? 이런 천하에...
- 뭐가?
What?
She was unconscious, man.
- 의식도 없었잖아
- 너무 예쁘길래...
Well, she was beautiful, and...
I stole a pair ofher panties
as well.
팬티도 슬쩍한걸
Jesus!
What?
- 미쳤다!
- 왜? 입던 것도 아닌데
It's not like--
I mean, theywere clean and all.
Don't tell me this stuff, man!
I don'twanna hearthis shit!
- 변태 같은 소리 그만해
- 입던 거 아냐
[Patrick]
Theywere clean!
[Stan ] What? D-Don't!Stop!
- 닥치고 일이나 해
- 하면 되잖아
[Patrick]
Okay. Yeah!All right!
[Stan ] We got work to do.
[ Computer Beeps ]
[Stan ]
Give me mypapers.
[ Crunching ]
[ Slurps ]
[ Patrick ]
There's, um--
[ Sighs ]
실은... 얘기 안 끝났어
There's more.
After we did her, I kind of...
삭제작업 끝낸 다음
데이트 신청했어
went to where she works
and asked her out.
뭘 해?
[Stan ]
You what?
- 말도 안 돼...
- 그건 너무...
[ Mutters ]
Jesus.
Jesus, Patrick!
Do you have... any idea...
파렴치한 짓이야!
how unethical--
그 정도는 아니다, 뭐
[ Laughing ]
It's not really that bad.
What? Get that look offyour face.
What's wrong?
그렇게 보지 마
뭐 어때서?
여자 팬티를 훔쳤다며!
[Stan Continues, Echoing]
Patrick,you stole a girl's panties!
[ High-pitched Giggling ]
[ Laughing ]
There's someone here.
누군가 있어
He stole your underwear.
걔가 네 팬티 훔쳤대
[ Voice Wavering, Electronically Altered ]
I don't see anyone.
누가 있다고 그래
[Clock Ticking]
[TV: Man Talking,
Audience Laugh Track ]
[ Clementine ]Joel?
조엘, 내 부츠 어디 있어?
Where are my boots?
그걸 왜 보여주는데?
영어 몰라?
[ TV: Man ]
Why are you showing me poisons?
Can'tyou understand English?
" Potions," I said.
Potions.
1회분이라고 했잖아
1회분
[ Laugh Track Continues ]
[ TV: Grandpa Munster]
Love potion, please.
마약 주세요!
내가 너 때문에 아주 미친다
I'm fucking crawling
out of my skin!
Should've left you
at the flea market.
벼룩시장에 두고 올 걸
[TV: Grandpa Munster]
First thing to do is--
중독되는 거 아니야?
[ Chuckles ]
sift in a cup
ofpowdered whale heart.
마구 먹어대다가 말이지
Wanna go?
갈래?
- 애기 갖고 싶어
- 나중에 얘기해
I want to have a baby.
[ Chuckles ]
Let's talk about it later.
No! I want to have a baby.
싫어, 애기 가질래
I don't think we're ready.
- 준비가 안 됐어
- 너나 그렇지
You're not ready.
Clem, do you really think
you could take care of a kid?
- 애를 키울 순 있고?
- 뭐?
[ Scoffs ]
What?
[ Mutters ]
I don't wanna
talk about it here.
- 여기서 말하긴 그래
- 그딴 건 왜 묻는 건데?
I can't hearyou.
I can never the fuck understand
whatyou're saying.
말하기 싫대도!
[ Whispering ]
I don't wanna talk about this!
Fucking ventriloquist!
사람 기막히게 해 놓고
꽁무니 빼면 다야?!
We're fucking
gonna talk about it!
I... don't... want... to--
You can't just say something like that
and sayyou don't wanna talk about it!
- 미안해
- 나 좋은 엄마 될 수 있어
[ Whispering ]
I'm sorry, Clem.
I'd make a fucking good mother!
I love children, I'm creative and smart,
and I'd make a fucking great mother!
Oh, God-- Mmm!
똑 부러지게 키울 수 있다고
[ Voice Echoing ]
It's you,Joel. It's you
who can't commit to anything!
문제는 너야
희생하기 싫다 이거지
It's going! It's going!
You have no idea how luckyyou are
I'm interested in you!
- 기억이 사라져!
- 넌 봉 잡은 줄 알아
[Voice Fading, Echoing ]
Maybe I should end this
right here,Joel!
- 여기서 끝내자
- 좋아
벼룩시장에 떨궈 놓고 갈 테니
Leaveyou at the flea market
with this stupid costumejewelry!
It's done. This is crap.
Maybeyou could find yourself
an antique rocking chair to die in!
All the pain, confusion--
죽을 때 앉을
흔들의자나 장만해
[Doorbell Rings ]
Oh. Hi, Patrick.
Hi, Mary. How's it goin'?
- 패트릭
- 왔어?
Hey,you.
Oh, it's freezing outside.
밖이 너무 추워
- 금방 찾았고?
- 응
[Stan ]
Find us okay?
[Mary] Yeah.
Mmm.
Hot!
좋아라
Poor guy.
불쌍하다!
Mmm? Oh.
Don't you have
anything real to drink?
- 술 같은 건 없어?
- 안 찾아봤는데
Uh, we haven't really
checkedyet.
Patrick?
Uh, yeah.
- 뒤져 봐라
- 내가 할게
Uh, let me do the honors.
Mary hates me.
나 싫어하잖아
난 여자 복이 없나 봐
Never really had much luck
with the ladies.
팬티에 손 안 대면
또 아냐?
Maybe ifyou stop
stealing their panties.
[Typing On Keyboard]
[Patrick Whispering]
Stan. Stan.
- 스탠, 더 있어
- 안 돼
There's more.
No!
Yes.
Hey, hey!
[ Mock Whispering ]
[Stan Laughing]
들었어
Oh, you didn't want any,
did you, Patrick?
- 너도 마실래?
- 아니, 됐어
Uh, no, that's okay.
Wait.
'망각한 자는 복이 있나니
실수조차 잊기 때문이라'
"Blessed are the forgetful,
for they get the better
even oftheir blunders."
[ Clink]
[ Laughing ]
Oh.
Oh!
[Patrick Laughing]
Mmm!
[ Groans ]
That's Nietzsche.
Beyond Goodand Evil.
니체가 '선악을 넘어'에서
한 말이야
- 잠언집에서 봤어
- 그게 뭔데?
I found it in my Bartlett's.
What's your Bartlett's?
유명한 말만 인용해 놓은 책이야
It's a quote book, Patrick.
It's a book of quotations.
I think Howard
will be in Bartlett's
one day.
우리 선생님 말도 적어야 돼
물론!
명언제조기잖아
Definitely.
Howard is pure Bartlett's.
[ Crash ]
[MaryLaughs ]
God!
[Patrick Laughing]
Can you wake him up?
- 깰 수도 있어?
- 그건 불가능해
[Patrick Laughing]
You can't wake him up.
[ Patrick Continues Laughing]
[ Stan Yells ]
Mmm.
[ Moans ]
왜 자기 얘긴 안 해?
You don't tell me things,Joel.
난 숨기는 거 없는데
I'm an open book.
치부까지도 다 털어놨다고
I tell you everything.
Every damn embarrassing thing.
You don't trust me.
날 못 믿는구나
Constantly talking
isn't necessarily communicating.
계속 떠들어야
마음이 전해지는 건 아냐
I don't do that.
누가 그러재?
널 알고 싶을 뿐이야
I want to knowyou.
Hmm?
나 계속 떠든 적 없어
매도하지 마!
I don't constantlytalk.
Jesus!
People have to
share things,Joel.
서로 나눠야 하는 거야
그러면서 정이 들지
Mm-hmm.
That's what intimacy is.
I'm really pissed
thatyou said that to me.
- 그걸 갖고 면박을 주냐!
- 미안해
I'm sorry.
Itjust-- reallyjust
isn't that interesting.
내가 워낙 맹숭하게 살아
일기라도 읽어 볼래
[Clementine]
I wanna readsome ofthosejournals
you're constantlyscribbling in.
What doyou write in there
ifyou don't have any thoughts
orpassions or...
뭘 쓴단 건 생각과 열정
사랑이 있다는 거니까
Iove?
[Joel's Voice ]
November 1 9, 2003.
2003년 11월 19일
또 중국집에서 저녁을 때웠다
Dinner at Kang's again.
우리도 딱한 커플이
돼가는 걸까
Are we like those poor couples...
you feel sorry for in restaurants?
둘이 멀뚱하게 앉아
먹어대기만 하는
Are we the dining dead?
I can't stand the idea of us bei ng
a couple people think that about.
그건 생각만 해도
너무 끔찍해
예쁘다
[ Whispers ]
I like that.
How's the chicken?
- 치킨 어때?
- 맛있어
Good.
More?
No. No. Thankyou.
- 더 줘?
- 아니, 됐어
[Joel's Voice ]
She's gonna be drunk
andstupid now.
또 취해선 황당한 짓 하겠지
Hey, would you
do me a favor...
머리 감고 나면
비누에 묻은 머리칼 좀 뗄래?
and clean the goddamn hair off the soap
when you're done in the shower?
Yeah. Oh. Yeah.
It's really...
- 그래, 더러웠겠다
- 난...
- Gross.
- gross.
- 그냥...
- 찝찝했구나
- It's just--
- Repulsive.
찝찝했어
It's repulsive.
[Phone Beep Dialing]
[ Line Ringing ]
[Stan ]
Patrick, can we get through this?
일 좀 하자, 패트릭?
Patrick.
안녕, 오렌지
[Patrick ]
Hey, Tangerine.
[ Clementine On Phone ]
Oh, Patrick, it's you.
패트릭이구나
나 지금 너무 비참해
[ Sighs ]
I'm so miserable right now.
[ Patrick ]
Why? What's wrong?
[ Clementine ] I don 't know.
- 왜 그래?
- 몰라, 모든 게 혼란스럽기만 해
[ Voice Electronical ly Altered ]
Excuse me?
I'm so confused!
Can I help you
find something, sir?
[ Patrick ]
Confused? What are you confused about?
Everything's fine.
뭐가 혼란스러운데?
아무 일도 없잖아
[ Voice Electronical ly Altered ]
Baby, come here.
[ Patrick ]
Scared ofwhat?
- 나 사랑해?
- 물론이지
[ Clementine ]
Do you love me?
[ Patrick ] Ofcourse I do.
[ Whispers ]
Where's the self-help section?
교양서적은 어디 있지?
[ Clementine Sobbing]
Do you think I'm ugly?
- 나 못생겼어?
- 아니, 너 예뻐
[ Patrick ]
No! You're beautiful!
[ Dishes Rattle ]
- 내가 가야겠다
- 안 돼
Maybe I should come over.
[ Clementine ]
No, no.
I don't know.
I-I'm a mess, Patrick.
나 몰골 엉망이야
[ Patrick ]
Well,just let me come over.
I'll cheeryou up.
- 내가 가서 기분 풀어줄게
- 알았어
[ Clementine ]
Okay.
Stan, can I leave for a whi le?
My gi rlfriend's really upset.
잠깐 나갔다 올게
여자친구가 힘들어해
남의 기억 지우다 말고
We're right in the middle
of erasing this poor man's--
[ Garbled ]
Let him go, Stan!
가라고 해
내가 도우면 되지, 뭐
[ Garbled ]
Let him go. I'll help.
See?
How hard can it be?
- 내가 싫어서 보내고 싶어해
- 가라
- She hates me.
She wants me to go.
- Go.
All right.
I'll be right over, Tangerine.
고마워
금방 갈게, 오렌지
예뻐?
You like?
[ Laughing ]
Oh, man!
- 추리닝 색깔에 맞췄지
- 맘에 들어, 꼭 오렌지 같아
I matched my sweatshirt exactly.
I like it.
You do?
You look like a tangerine.
Ohh!
"Clemen-teen" the tangerine.
Mmm! Juicy!
오렌지 소녀 클레멘타인!
- 상큼한 과즙이 줄줄
- 맘에 들어
And seedless.
I like that.
I like tangerines!
나 오렌지 광이지롱!
Can you see me doing ducks?
- 그림자 오리 볼래?
- 오렌지
Tangerine.
Joel. Ducks.
Quack-quack.
How does he know
to call you that?
How did who know?
- 그걸 어떻게 알았대?
- 누가 뭘 알아?
Oh, my God. Clem?
[Mary]
This is prettycool.
맙소사!
클레멘타인!
클래쉬야말로
제대로 된 록밴드야
That's what
they called themselves.
The Clash--
the only band that mattered.
- 다 이유가 있다고
- 멋져
They called themselves that
for a reason.
It's amazing, isn't it?
Like social justice--
Yeah, it's totally incredible.
'격돌'이란 뜻으로
사회정의를 외쳤지
What Howard
gives to the world.
우리 선생님도 기여했어
Yeah.
[Beeping]
- 하긴...
- 사람들을 다시 시작하게 했지
To let people begin again.
[ Punches Keys ]
It's beautiful.
아기를 보면 순수하고
You look at a baby,
and it's so pure and so free
and so clean.
자유롭고 순결하지만
And adults are, like,
this mess ofsadness...
어른은 슬픔과 공포에...
찌들었어
and... phobias.
Howard just makes it all go away.
그걸 선생님이 없애주잖아
Oh, myGod.
오, 이런
Baby, what's going on?
I don't know.
I don't know!
- 자기야, 왜 그래?
- 나도 몰라
I'm lost, I'm scared,
괜히 무섭고
내가 사라지는 거 같아
I feel like I'm disappearing.
살갗도 벗겨지고
늙어가는 거 같다고
Disappearing?
My skin's coming off!.
I'm getting old!
Nothing makes any sense to me!
You're not getting old.
- 늙긴 누가!
- 말이 안 된단 거 나도 잘 알아
Nothing makes any sense.
Ohh, Tangerine.
- 오렌지야...
- 혼란스러워
Nothing makes any sense.
- 정말 모르겠어
- 괜찮아, 걱정 마
Nothing makes any sense, Patrick.
It's okay. It's okay.
춤추러 나가자
나와 몬타우크 갈래?
Hey, let's go out dancing. Yeah?
You wanna go out to Montaukwith me?
Montauk?
Yeah.
- 몬타우크?
- 아니!
No! Come up to Boston with me.
Sure. Yeah.
We can go next weekend.
- 보스턴이 낫겠다
- 다음 주말에 가자
아니, 지금 가야 돼
꽁꽁 언 찰스강을 봐야겠어
No, no. Now. Now.
Yeah. I have to go now.
I have to see
the frozen Charles now.
♪♪ [Rock]
[ Giggling ]
[Answering Machine:Joel]
Hi, it'sJoel.
조엘입니다
Um, leave a message after the beep
and I'll get back to you.
메시지 남겨주시면 연락 드리죠
[ Beeps ]
받아 봐
[ Patrick On Answering Machine ]
Pick up! Pick up, man!
W-W-W-W-Whoa.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
[ Laughing ]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
Hello? Yeah, what's up?
여보세요
왜 그래?
I got into a little situation
with the old lady.
여자친구한테 문제가 생겼어
혼자 해주면 안 될까?
Can you handle things tonight alone?
I'm really sorry, man.
- 정말 미안하다
- 걱정 마, 자동조종 걸어놨어
Don't worry about it.
I got it under control, man.
[ Continues Giggling ]
He's pretty much on autopilot
right now anyway.
Thanks, Stan. I oweyou big-time.
- 너밖에 없다
- 이만 끊을게
Dude, I gotta go.
I gotta go.
[ Muttering ]
Charles.
찰스강...
Come on, Charles.
'자기와 찰스강에 있다니
지금 죽어도 좋아'
"Look! You and me on the Charles River.
I could die right now, Clem.
'이렇게 행복한 기분
난생 처음... '
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm just exactlywhere I want--"
- 너무 기대돼
- 나도 기대만빵이야
I'm so excited. Yea.
I'm excited too!
Cool.
Oh, uh, I, uh--
실은...
I got you this...
What?
thing, um--
줄 게 있어
Happy earlyValentine's Day.
발렌타인데이 선물
미리 땡길게
Oh!
- 와아, 뭔데?
- 글쎄, 열어봐
Wow. What is it?
Uh, I don't know.
Open it up.
Oh.
너무 예뻐!
It-- It's gorgeous!
- 맘에 들어?
- 딱 내 취향이야
- You like it?
- Yeah. It's just my taste. Really.
맘에 드는 액세서리
받아보긴 처음이야
I've never gone out with a guy
who bought me a piece ofjewelry I liked.
Thankyou.
고마워
Let's go.
Okay.
- 가자
- 그래
- 조엘?
- 왜, 오렌지야?
Joely?
Yeah, Tangerine?
나 못생겼어?
Am I ugly?
Mm-mmm.
When I was a kid,
I thought I was.
어릴 땐 그렇게 생각했어
[ Sighs ]
Can't believe I'm crying already.
벌써 눈물이 나네
Sometimes I think people
don't understand how lonelyit is
to be a kid.
아이로 사는 건
참 외로운 거 같아
Like you don't matter.
자긴 그거 모를걸
So, I'm eight...
나 8살 때...
and I have these toys,
인형을 모았거든
these dolls.
제일 좋아한 밉둥이를
'클레멘타인'이라 부르곤
My favorite is this ugly girl doll
who I call Clementine.
And I keep yelling at her:
맨날 소리쳤어
못생기지 말고 예뻐지라고
"You can't be ugly! Be pretty!"
It's weird.
황당하지만
걔가 변신하면
Like ifl can transform her,
[ Sniffles ]
마법처럼
나도 예뻐질 거 같아서
I would magically change too.
You're pretty.
- 너 예뻐
- 자기야
J oely, don't ever leave me.
- 날 버리지 마
- 눈이 부실만큼 예뻐
Pretty. Pretty.
[Joel's Voice ]
Mierzwiak, please
let me keep this memory.
이 기억만큼은 남겨주세요
Just this one.
나 자기 손 잡을래
[ Clementine ]
I don't wanna holdyour hand.
Come on.
Whoo!
Whoa!
[ Clementi ne Whoops ]
Stop it!
그만해
[ Clementine Laughing ]
지금 죽어도 좋아
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just...
나 너무... 행복하다
happy.
I've never felt that before.
이런 기분 처음이야
Mmm.
이런 순간을... 늘 꿈꿔왔어
I'm just exactly...
where I wanna be.
Clem?
클레멘타인?
I wanna call it off.
취소할래요
내 말 알아듣죠?
I'll giveyou a sign.
I wanna call it off!.
다 취소한다고요
내 말 들려요?
기억 지우기 싫다고요!
Can you hear me?
I don't want this anymore!
I wanna call it off!.
[Stereo: Man ]
♪ Whenyou ain't got nothing to do ♪
♪ I think I'll marryyou♪♪
거기 아무도 없어요?
[ Screaming ]
Is anybody there?
[ Loud Groaning ]
Clementine?
Joel?
누구 없어요?!
Clement--
Joely?
- 클레멘타인
- 조엘
Clem!
Joel?
- 어디?
- 조엘
Clem!
클레멘타인
What?
We gotta go.
- 가야 돼
- 어딜?
What? Where?
I have an idea
ofhow to stop this.
- 이걸 멈출 방법이 있어
- 뭘 멈춰?
Stop what?
Joely.
Come on, Clem.
- 조엘
- 어서
Smell my armpit!
No!
- 겨드랑이 냄새 맡아 봐
- 싫대도
Don't tickle me!
Don't make me smell you.
Smell my pits!
- 간지럼 그만 태워
- 맡아 봐
No.
Good.
집중해야 돼
Concentrate, Clem.
We gotta get back
to the office.
그 회사에 가야 돼
녹음테이프가 있을 거야
There was a tape recorder.
No, not the picture.
그림 말고!
Not the picture.
저리 다시 가보자
Where is it? Back here.
Come on!
[ Clementine ]
Oh, look at me.
Hey, I look good there.
나 좀 봐!
예쁜 거 같아
파일은 극비라
보여드릴 수는 없고
[ Mierzwiak ]
Look, our files are confidential,
Mr. Barish,
so I can't showyou evidence.
크루친스키 양은 힘들어하면서
Suffice it to say that Miss, uh--
Miss Kruczynski...
was not happy
and she wanted to move on.
다 잊고 싶어했습니다
기억나는 것부터...
Good. Now, tell me about Clementine.
[Joel]
Just tell me everything you remember.
- 기억나는 거 다 말해보랬어
- 그날 뭘 봤지?
That's what he said. Then--
What did we see that day?
No, wait.
Oh, look! Hey!
저 봐!
할머니한테 가자
Shit!
We're going to see
my grandma.
Joel, why-- No, I don't want to--
Joel, please!
We're not going on a train.
- 기차 타면 안 돼
- 나 그만 뛸래
Don't make me run anymore.
Come on!
Mierzwiak!
박사님!
Do we always have to run?
Mierzwiak!
- 맨날 뛰어야 돼?
- 박사님
[Dog Barking]
Please.
제발...
So, why don't we begin
byyou telling me...
기억나는 거부터 차근차근...
everythingyou can remember.
박사님, 깨워주세요!
[Joel]
Mierzwiak! Wake me up!
Oh, I-I'm sorry, Mr. Barish.
죄송한데 상황을 잘 아시잖아요
I thoughtyou understood
what was going on here.
I don't know.
You're erasing her from me.
내게서 그녈 지우고
그녀한테서 날 지웠어
You're erasing me from her--
I don't know.
잘 모르지만
당신 소관이잖아
You've got this thing.
I'm in my bed. I know it.
난 지금 내 뇌 속에
들어와 있다고
I'm in my brain.
지금의 나도 상상일 뿐인데
어떻게 돕겠어요?
I'm part ofyourimagination too,Joel.
How can I help you
from there?
Uh, I'm insideyourhead too.
I'myou.
나도 당신의 상상이 만든
허상이라고요
[ Grunts ]
Sorry.
- 죄송해요
- 누구죠?
Look. Who's that?
Oh, he-he works for us.
여기 직원인데...
That's, uh, Pa-a-a-a-atrick,
'패애애애트릭'
우리 자기죠
babyboy.
He's stealing my identity.
내 물건을 훔쳐선
내 행세를 해요
He stole my stuff.
He's, uh, seducing my girlfriend
with mywords and my things.
내 말투 흉내 내며
여자친구를 꼬신다고요
He stole her underwear.
Oh,Jesus Christ!
속옷까지 훔쳤어요
기가 막혀서!
He stole her underwear.
[DoorCloses ]
I could die right now, Clem.
지금 죽어도 좋아
나 너무 행복하다
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm just exactlywhere
I want to be.
이런 기분 처음이야
이런 순간을 늘 꿈꿔왔어
I want to go home.
집에 갈래
Hey. What?
뭐?
Clem!
[ Grunting ]
클레멘타인!
Wait. Clem!
기다려 봐
Clem?
클레멘타인!
자길 지우고 있어
They're erasingyou.
[Dog Barks ]
I'm here!
[ Screams ]
여기 있지!
Clem, focus.
I hired them, okay?
[Laughing]
바보 같지만
내가 그자들을 고용했어
I'm so stupid.
진정하고 경치나 구경해
Sweetie, calm down.
Enjoy the scenery.
I need it to stop before I wake up
and I don't knowyou anymore.
깨어나서 널 잊기 전에
중단해야 돼
Okay, well, you know,
just tell them to cancel it then.
그럼 계약 취소한다고 해
What the hell are you talking about?
I can't just cancel it. I'm asleep.
지금 자고 있는데
어떻게 말을 해?
Wake yourself up!
- 그럼 일어나!
- 일어나라고?
Okay. You want me to wake up?
Okay. Great. All right.
Okay, here we go.
This makeyou happy ifl try?
Yeah.
안 되더라도 해봐?
I'll try really hard. Here we go.
That was a great idea.
최선을 다해 볼게
기발한 생각이야
Yeah. Okay.
금방이라도 깨어날 거 같네
Boy, that's working
like gangbusters.
[MaryLaughs ]
Don't! That tickles me!
[Stan ] Oh, my goodness.
간지러워!
Oh, my God. What is that?
Jesus Christ! What the--
- 아니, 이건 뭐래?
- 반점이야!
[ Mary]
It's a birthmark!
I t did work, for a second,
잠깐 깨어났었어
근데...
but I couldn't--
I couldn't move.
See?
- 그것 봐
- 움직여지질 않았어
Oh, well, isn't that just another one
ofJoel's self-fulfilling prophecies?
지레 그러려니 한 거 아냐?
나한테 어깃장...
It's more important
to prove me wrong
than to actually--
그 얘긴 하고 싶지 않아
Look, I don't want to
discuss this right now, okay?
Fine.
좋아
Then what? I'm listening.
무슨 얘기 할래?
- 들을 준비 됐어
- 글쎄...
I don't know.
You erased me.
네가 날 지워서
내가 이런 거잖아
That's why I'm here.
That's why I'm doing this
in the first place.
미안해, 알다시피
내가 좀 욱하잖아
I'm sorry.
You-- You!
You know me. I'm impulsive.
그래서 네가 좋아
That's what I love
aboutyou.
[Beeping]
[Clementine ]
Joel?
- 조엘
- 응
[Joel] Mm-hmm?
I have anotheridea
forthis problem.
이렇게 하면 어떨까?
This is a memory of me,
네 기억은 이런 거잖아
가령 내 아랫도릴 본 후
the wayyou wanted
to have sex on the couch afteryou
looked down at my crotch.
날 갖고 싶단 식이지
What?
Joel, the eraser guys
are coming here,
그럼 지우러 오기 전에
날 딴 데 데려가는 거야
so what ifyou take me
somewhere else,
somewhere
where I don't belong,
엉뚱한 기억 속에서
아침까지 숨어있는 거지
and we hide there
till morning?
[ Sighs ]
Oh, man. I can't remember
anything withoutyou.
너 없인
아무것도 기억이 안 나
[ Scoffs ]
Tsk, that's very sweet,
but try, okay?
- 듣긴 좋지만 해봐
- 알았어
Okay.
♪ 쌩쌩쌩 노저어 가자
♪ Row, row, rowyourboat
gentlydown the stream ♪
♪ Merrily, merrily
merrily, merrily ♪
♪ 신나라, 신나라, 신나라
♪ Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream ♪
♪ 쌩쌩쌩 노저어 가자
♪ Row, row, rowyour boat ♪
[ Both ]
♪ Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily ♪
♪ 신나라, 신나라, 신나라
♪ Life is but a dream ♪
[ Boy]
♪ Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily ♪
♪ Merrily, merrily
merrily, merrily ♪
- 인생은 꿈일 뿐
- ♪ 쌩쌩쌩 노저어 가자
♪ Life is but a dream
Row, row, row your boat ♪
It's working!
♪ Row, row, row your boat ♪
되네!
역시 난 천재야!
♪ Gently down the stream ♪♪
[ Clementine ]
I'm a genius!
[ Giggling ]
Joel?
조엘?
Where'dyou go?
어디 갔어?
나도 데려가야지!
I'm supposed to come too!
그릇 갖고 오게
조엘 좀 봐줄래요?
[ Woman ] Listen, I'mjust gonna
go get a salad bowl. Can you stir the soup
and keep an eye onJoel?
[ Woman #2 ]
Sure.
Hejust likes to be near me.
- 나 떨어지길 싫어해
- 그럴게요
Absolutely!
Clem?
- 클레멘타인?
- 됐다
It worked.
My God, look at this! Wow!
웬일이니, 됐어!
It worked! Look!
Look at this dress, man!
이 드레스 좀 봐!
갖고 가고 싶다
Oh, my God! Look at it!
I wish I could take it with me.
Who am I?
- 내가 누구야?
- 햄린 부인
Mrs. Hamlyn.
Right. Mrs. Hamlyn.
- 알았어
- 난 4살쯤 됐나 봐, 이럴 수가!
I must be about four.
Oh, my gosh.
Found the salad bowl,
so I'm serving salad and string beans.
그릇 찾았으니까 샐러드 담을게요
애는 괜찮죠?
Is he okay under there?
Peanut, areyou all right?
청소할 게 산더미 같아요
God, honestly, I feel like
I could clean up all day.
- 콩 좀 씻어줄래요?
- 문제없어요
Listen, would you hate me ifl asked you
to clean some string beans?
No, not at all.
Oh, my God.
I love this kitchen.
- 부엌 끝내준다!
- 고마워요
Thankyouso much.
She's not looking at me.
바빠서 난 거들떠보질 않네
She's busy.
She's not looking at me.
[ Laughing ]
No one ever looks at me.
I want my mommy.
내겐 엄마가 필요한데
Oh, babyJoel.
Hey,Joely!Joely!
오, 우리 애기!
Is everylittle peanut
underthere okay?
Mm-hmm! He's fine.
- 꼬맹이 별일 없죠?
- 잘 놀아요
Do you have something to drink?
- 술 좀 없어요?
- 이 시간에?
Wouldyou drink
a cocktail at this hour?
I mean, I know it's not 5:00.
I would die for a vodka.
Oh, hang on.
Let me check if I have that.
- 보드카가 절실해요
- 찾아보죠
Okay! I'm just
gonna wait right here.
Joel! Hey, no, sweetie.
그럼 안 돼
[ Grunting ]
Uh,Joely.
나더러 자기 지키래
식탁 밑으로 들어가
Yourmotherwants me to mindyou.
Get back underthe table.
Ice cream.
- 아이스크림!
- 저녁 먹고 나서 먹어
Ice cream.
No, not until after,you know,
you've hadyour dinner.
[ Angry Grunt ]
Come on,Joel!
조엘, 제발
Joel, grow up!
- 의젓하게 굴어
- 날 떠나지 마
Don't leave me, Clem.
Oh, my God, Clem.
[ Sobbing]
- 이럼 어떡해
- 잘 되고 있어
This is sort of warped.
I'm scared.
- 엄마 불러줘
- 울지 마, 괜찮아
[ Crying ]
I want my mommy!
Don't cry, baby Joel.
Baby Joel, it's okay.
Joel.Joely.Joel!
뚝 그쳐!
우리 잘 숨어있잖아
Stop it! Look, I think it's working.
Look, we're hidden,Joel. Look!
이럼 어떨까?
Hey, honey, look.
Wait there.
기다려 봐
My crotch is still here,
just as you remembered it.
- 내 아랫도리는 아직도 건재해
- 징그러
Yuck.
[Buzzing]
It stopped.
- 멈췄어
- 뭐가?
What?
It stopped erasing.
지우길 멈췄어
Oh, shit.
제기랄, 미치겠다!
This is terrible.
He's offthe map.
회로에서 벗어났어
Where?
I don't know where!
What doyou mean? I don't know where!
- 어디 갔는데?
- 낸들 알아!
This is bad.
This is very, very bad news.
Where are my glasses?
완전 낭패인데
안경이 어디 갔지?
Okay. Crap.
죽겠군!
이제 뭘 어쩌지?
Okay. What do we do?
What do I do?
What shall we do?
I don't know what to do.
- 어떡해!
- 모르겠어
- What shall we do?
- Crap. Crap. I don't know!
- 어쩌냐고?
- 모르겠다니까!
- I just said that I don't know what to do.
- I'm sorry. What do we do?
- 미안해, 어쩜 좋아!
- 네가 그러니까 더 미치겠어
I don't know.
Now, look,you're freaking me out.
Mellow out.
Well, you have to do something.
He could wake up all half-baked.
- 그러다 중간에 깨어나면 어떡해!
- 가만히 좀 있어
Quiet. You're freaking me out.
Shh. Shh.
빵 굽다가 만 격이야
멋진 말이네
All gooey and-- and half-baked.
Hmm, that sounds so good.
Oh, shit!
I'm hungry.
- 그 말 하니까 출출한걸
- 제기랄
Oh, shit.
Oh! Oh!
What? Oh! What, what?
What?
왜, 왜 그래?
- We should call Howard.
- No way. No, sir, man.
- 선생님 부르자
- 안 돼, 나 혼자 할 수 있어
This is my--
I can handle this.
I can't call Howard.
He's an unbaked cookie.
굽다 만 빵이잖아
He's-- There's no time
to fuck around.
- 지금 우길 시간 없어
- 그냥 혼자 해결할래
I got this under control.
What areyou talking about?
- 말이 되는 소릴 해!
- 내가 전화할게
Stop fucking around!
Okay, I'll call Howard.
[Phone Rings ]
[ Rings ]
Hello.
Hello, Howard?
Hey, it's Stan.
선생님, 스탠인데요
Um, I'm working on this guy
down here, and we seem to have
lost him for a moment,
그 남자 작업하다가
잠깐 잃어버렸는데
and, uh, I can't--
I can't bring him back up.
- 못 찾겠어요
- 사라지기 전 상황은?
Okay, uh, tell me what happened
before he disappeared.
Well, I wasn't sure, really,
'cause I was away from the monitor
for a minute...
실은 잠깐 모니터를
못 봤거든요
and I had it on autopilot
because I had to, uh--
화장실 가느라
자동조종 걸어놔서요
I had to pee.
- 패트릭은?
- 아파서 집에 갔어요
Where's Patrick?
Patrick? Patrick had to
go home sick.
Ah, geez.
이런...
Okay, what's the address?
I know. I'm so sorry.
- 주소는?
- 죄송해요
That's okay. Come on.
[Stan ]
I'm at 159 South Village.
록빌 센터 아파트 1E예요
Yeah.
Apartment 1E.
Rockville Center.
Mary?
He's coming right now.
Yeah?
매리, 지금 오신대
I'm staying.
[Bottles Clinking]
- 그냥 있을래
- 얼른 짐 챙겨
- Get your stuff, Mary.
- I 'm staying.
I thinkyou should go.
Hell, no.
- 가는 게 좋아
- 싫어
Mary-- Shit.
I am so stoned.
Please, Mary.
- 나 마약에 취했어
- 매리
You have to go.
Stop being stoned, Mary.
- 너 가야 돼
- 마약한 거 들키긴 싫은데
I don't want him
to see me stoned.
Mary,you have no idea howmuch trouble
we're gonna get into ifHoward comes--
I look like shit!
놀다가 그런 거 아시면
난리가...
Joely, stop it!Joel!
Look! Hey,Joel!
조엘, 뚝 그치지 못해!
[ Blubbering ]
Joel!
I want her to pick me up.
엄마한테 안아 달랠래
그 생각밖에 없어
It's weird how strong
that desire is.
Joel, look at me! Look.
날 봐
아침에도 날 기억하곤
You'll remember me
in the morning,
and you'll come to me,
and you'll tell me about us,
and we'll start over.
내게 와서 다 말하고
다시 시작하는 거야
Pat? I just-- Pat?
패트리샤, 칵테일 마시자면서요
I thought we could have
a little cocktail.
That Patrick guy--
he's copying me.
패트릭이란 애가
날 표절했어
What Patrick guy?
- 패트릭이 누구야?
- 내 아파트에 와 있는 녀석!
That guy!
What?
He's here in my apartment.
He's one ofthose eraser guys.
네 기억 지우다가
너한테 맛이 가선
He fell foryou when theywere doing you,
and now he's introduced himself
like he doesn't even knowyou,
곧바로 접근하곤
너와 사귀고 있다고
and you guys are dating.
Really? Is he cute?
정말?
귀엽게 생겼어?
Clem,
there's nothing wrong with you.
아무 문제 없어
You're the most wonderful
person I've ever met.
넌 내가 만난 여자 중에
제일 멋져
You-- You're kind,
상냥하고 예쁘고
[ Sobbing ]
beautiful...
and smart and funny...
똑똑하고 재미있고
and... nice.
- 착해
- 뭐?
What?
Okay. All right.
됐어
Okay. Oh!
Move, move, move!
Come on. Let's go.
Careful, careful.
비켜 봐, 가자고
Fine.
Oh, my God. I'm still stoned.
[ Groans ]
나 아직도 맛이 갔어
Those eyedrops you gave me
didn't do shit.
네가 준 안약도
도움이 안 돼
[ Chuckles ]
[Doorbell Ringing]
[ Clears Throat ]
Be cool. Cool.
흥분하지 마
Hello, Mary.
What are you doing here?
Oh, hi, Howard.
- 여긴 웬일이야?
- 도와주러 왔어요
She was just here to help out.
이 과정에 대해
확실히 알고 싶어서요
I wanted to understand as much
as I could about the procedure
as possible.
I think it's important for myjob
to understand the innerworkings...
속속들이 이해하는 게
중요할 것도 같고
ofthe work that we do.
제 일은 아니지만
동료 일이니까
Well, not that I do,
but the work that is done...
by people... where I also work,
the work of my colleagues.
같이 일하는 사람 일도
알아둬야죠
All right, well,
let's see ifwe can, uh,
어떻게 된 건지 알아보지
get to the bottom ofthis,
shall we?
Uh, yeah. Um--
Well, that's odd.
I already tried that.
- 이상하군
- 벌써 해봤어요
Did you try going
through the C-gate?
Yeah, ofcourse.
- C게이트로도?
- 당연한 말을!
해봤다고요
I mean... yes.
Yeah.
[ Clears Throat ]
All right.
좋아
You want to get linked up?
Yeah.
- 연결하겠나?
- 네
All right.
I already-- I ran
the utility programs,
유틸리티프로그램도
소용이 없길래
and I had nothing there,
so I checked all the memories
against the printed logs.
출력데이터를 참고로
기억을 검토해봤어요
Here, Howard.
Okay.
- 선생님, 앉으세요
- 고마워
I gotyou a chair.
There you go.
Oh, thankyou.
You're welcome.
Whew!
별말씀을요
All right, I'm gonna--
I'm gonna go through
the entire memory,
이렇게 하지
기억을 전부 훑어가며
뭐가 있나 알아볼게
see ifsomething comes up.
♪ Oh, my darling
Oh, my darling ♪
♪ 내 사랑아, 내 사랑아
♪ 나의 사랑 클레멘타인
♪ Oh, my darling Clementine ♪
♪You were lost
and gone forever ♪
I love being bathed in the sink.
싱크대에서 목욕하면
안전한 거 같아 좋더라
♪ Dreadful sorry, Clementine ♪♪
Such a feeling ofsecurity.
I've never seen you happier,
babyJoel.
[ Giggling ] Hmm!
이렇게 행복해하는 거
처음 봐
There it is.
여기 있군, 이게 왜
기억회로에서 빠졌을까?
I don't understand
why it's offthe map like that.
What the heck
was he doing there?
저기서 뭐 하는 거죠?
[ Grunts ]
[Gagging]
[ Coughing ]
His eyes are open.
눈을 떴어
- Has this happened before with him?
- [Stan ] No.
- 전에도 이랬나?
- 아뇨
Oh, this is--
this is not good. No.
이러면 안 되는데
I'm gonna have to--
I'm gonna have to give him this.
이걸 놔야겠군
[ Gasps, Panting ]
Can'tyou see I loveyou,
Antoine?
내 사랑이 느껴지지 않나요, 앙투안?
[Mierzwiak]
Okay, we're back in.
정상 회로에 들어섰군
[Mary]
Wow. That was beautiful
to watch, Howard.
참 감동적이네요
의사나 피아니스트 같아요
Like a surgeon
or a concert pianist
or something.
Thankyou, Mary.
고맙네
Um, Howard,
you should get some sleep.
I-I think I'll be fine now.
눈 좀 붙이세요
이젠 괜찮아요
Whycan'tyousee I loveyou,
Antoine?
내 사랑이 느껴지지 않나요, 앙투안?
Hmm. Lucky me.
그런 뜻에서
뽀뽀나 한 판 할까?
Lay one on me.
[ Kissing Sounds ]
Don't call me Antoine.
난 '앙투안'이 아니라
'월리'요
Myname is Wally.
Yes, I know,
알지만 월리란 이름은
너무 깨잖아요
but how can a woman love a man
with a name like Wally?
어머, 뭐죠?
Oh! Oh! What was that?
Hey.
My God, there's people
coming out ofyour butt.
- 그대 엉덩이에서 사람이 나왔어
- 정말요?
There is?
[ Giggling ]
- Got it.
- T angeri ne!
- 찾았다!
- 오렌지!
[ Cryi ng ]
What, J oel-- What are you doing?
We gotta go.
도망쳐야 돼, 어서!
Go on. Please, please, go.
Please go!
You can run,
but you can't hide.
- 이젠 못 숨을걸
- 빨리 와
Clem, come on!
There I am.
[ Tires Screech ]
나다!
That truck.
빌어먹을 트럭!
Doc? Please.
선생님, 제발!
[Distorted Voice ]
All right, let's begin
byyou telling me...
기억나는 거부터...
차근차근...
everything you remember--
That's strange.
He's in a memory
that we've already erased.
이상해요
이미 지운 기억 속에 있어요
Oh, well, at least
we know where he is.
He's back on track, right?
그래도 궤도 내에 있으니
다행이지
[ Sighs ]
Come on, Clem.
- 저항하는 거 같은데요
- 더는 안 뛸래
[Stan's Voice ]
He seems to have developedsome sort
ofresistance to the procedure.
I don't want to run anymore.
Shit.
미쳐!
Come on, come on.
Hide me somewhere deeper,
somewhere really buried.
- 빨리 와
- 아주 깊숙한 곳에 숨겨줘
Where?
Hide me in your humiliation.
- 어디?
- 창피한 기억 속에 숨겨
Humiliation.
[Boy]
Come on,you bigbaby!
- 창피한...
- 겁쟁아, 빨리 해!
[Joel's Voice ]
I'm sorry, okay?
[Angry Voices Overlapping]
[Joel's Voice ]
Let me driveyou home.
[ Child Yells ]
No!
안 돼!
- [ Mary] Bye, Howard.
- No, wait. Howard.
- 살펴가세요
- 잠깐만요
He's disappeared again.
- 또 사라졌어요
- 맙소사
Oh, dear.
[ Mary]
I'm so sorry, Howard.
- 면목 없네요
- 창피한 기억...
Humiliation.
- 창피한...
- 조엘
Hu-mi-lia--
Joel.
[ Sighs ]
I don't like it either.
이것도 아닌데
아지트 같은 걸 찾아야...
I'm just trying to find
horrible secret places to--
놀랄 일이 있어
Joel, honey, I have a surprise--
I just-- Oh, um--
Uh,you know what, honey?
I'mjust gonna askyou in the morning.
내일 아침에 물어볼게
[ Wheezing Laugh ]
Good night, sweetheart.
잘 자라
[ Laughing Continues ]
No.
I'm sorry,Joel.Joely.
Shut up.
- 나 때문에 미안해
- 듣기 싫어
Look! Joel!
일어나봐
조엘, 우리가 어디 있나 봐봐
Joel, look!
What?
Lookwhere we are!
Whoo!
여긴 들키기 십상이야
Clem, this isn't good.
Then hide me somewhere--
somewhere really buried.
아무도 못 찾을만한
깊숙한 곳에 숨겨줘
[ Children Shouting]
내려쳐!
Hit it! Hit it!
[Joel ]
I can't! I gotta go home.
집에 가야 돼
그냥 나중에 할게
I'll do it later!
[ Shouting Continues ]
Come on, you big sissy!
[ Shouting Stops ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Children ]
Ooh!
Ooh, he has a girlfriend!
- 애인도 있나 봐
- 너 까불면 가만 안 둔다
Wait. What am I doing?
You know something, Freddy?
And he loves her!
You don't scare me anymore.
Ow! Ow!
[ Groaning]
Joel!
그만 일어나
괜한 짓 하지 말고
Joely, get up.
Come on, it's not worth it.
Hit him! Hit him!
They're not worth it,Joel!
Tra-la-la-la-la! He's not listening!
그만들 놀려라
신경 쓰지 마
Come on,Joel.
Stupid!
바보!
[Joel's Voice ]
I'm so ashamed.
[ Clementine's Voice ] It's okay.
- 너무 창피해
- 괜찮아
You were a little kid.
Yeah?
꼬마 때 일인걸
Come on.
That's where I live-- lived.
내가 살던 집이야
그때 널 알았더라면...
I wish I knewyou
when I was a kid.
내 분홍모자 예뻐?
기분도 풀 겸 나 죽여 봐
Do you like my pink hat?
Here, look, feel better.
You can really kill me this time.
It's my turn.
Go. One, two, three.
I can? You're really gonna die though.
- 너 진짜 죽는다
- 하나, 둘, 셋!
Okay.
One, two, three.
You're dead.
[ Both Groaning ]
너 죽었어
Oh, my mom.
It's-- It's okay. We 're playing.
엄마다
그냥 노는 거지 죽이는 거 아니에요
Hi,Joel's mom.
He 's killing me.
It's not real.
- 나 죽인대요
- 벌써 죽었나?
Okay, are you deadyet?
죽어라!
You're dead!
[ Grunts ]
U h, I think I got the hang of this.
감은 잡았는데
이해가 안 가는군
I still don't understand it,
but I 'm finding him quickly enough.
어쨌든 금방 찾겠어
Clem!
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Muffled Grunting ]
[ Groans ]
[ Growling ]
조엘, 너 괜찮아?
Jo--Joely?
Areyou okay,Joel?
Joel? Joel?
[ Laughing ]
조엘, 조엘!
Oh, my God.
That was terrible.
못 살아, 그렇게 놀래키냐?
Okay, okay.
That was like three seconds.
Allright.
Let me do it one more time.
One more, then I get to go.
- 한번만 더 해줘
- 그 다음엔 나야
Okay.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Whoo!
[ Clementine Giggling ]
Look at this.
This is so cool!
- 봐봐
- 멋지다!
Cool. Look out! Look out!
조심해!
Ah!
Shit!
It's fluff.
푸석대
Our house!
우리 집이야!
Come on. Whoo-hoo!
Come on.
We gotta go!
- 가보자
- 가야 돼
Whoo!
Come on!
가보자!
We gotta go. Clem?
도망쳐야 돼
We gotta go.
Aah! Come on!
이러고 놀 시간 없어
No!
This is a really bad time
for this!
Get off me! Oh, God!
- 어딜 가는데?
- 가보면 재미있을 거야
I don't even know
where we're going.
It's gonna be fun. Come on.
이쪽이야
It's the best place.
No, this way.
- 아니, 저쪽이야
- 이쪽이래도
No, no, no. This way.
You're no help at all.
[ Shouts ]
도움이 안 돼요
What's wrong with you?
[ Laughing ]
- 그만해
- 이것 좀 놔봐!
Let go of me,Joel!
[ Grunts ]
I like watching you work,
Howard.
일하시는 게 멋져요
[ Chuckles ]
[ Grunts ]
I guess, uh--
나가서... 바람 좀 쐬고 올게요
I guess I'll go out
for-- for some air,
if nobody minds.
It looks likeyou have everything
under control here.
이제 정상을 찾은 거 같으니까
Yeah, that's, uh--
그래, 좋도록 해
that's fine.
[DoorCloses ]
Doyou like quotes, Howard?
명언구 좋아하세요?
What do you mean?
- 무슨?
- 왜, 있잖아요
Oh,you know,
like famous quotes?
I find reading them inspirational,
잠언집을 읽어보니
감명적이던데
and in my reading,
I've come across some
I thought you might like too.
선생님도 좋아하실 게
꽤 있더라고요
Oh, well, I--
I'd love to hear some.
들어보기나 하지
There's one that goes,
'망각한 자는 복이 있나니
실수조차 잊기 때문이라'
"Blessed are the forgetful,
for they get the better
even oftheir blunders."
That's Nietzsche, right?
Yeah.
- 니체로군
- 벌써 다 아시는군요
And here I thought I could tell you
something you didn't know.
Oh, no.
좋은 명언구를
함께 나누니 흐뭇한걸
It's-- It's a good quote.
I'm happywe both know it.
Yeah. Oh, and there's
this other one I like.
포프 알렉산더 것도 있는데...
It's by Pope Alexander,
and it goes--
AlexanderPope?
Oh, yeah.
- 알렉산더 포프?
- 맞다, 나도 참...
Yeah, shit.
포프 알렉산더라
하지 말자 해놓곤
It'sjust that I told myself
not to say "Pope Alexander"
andsound like a dope,
그렇게 말해버리네요
and then I go ahead and say it.
- 별 것도 아닌걸, 뭐
- 너무 자상하세요
It's no big deal.
You're such a sweetheart.
The quote goes, "How happy is
the blameless vestal's lot?
'처녀의 제비뽑기와'
'잊혀진 세상에 의해
잊혀가는 세상과'
"The world forgetting,
by the world forgot.
"Eternal sunshine
ofthe spotless mind.
'흠 없는 마음에 비추는
영원의 빛과'
Each prayer accepted
and each wish resigned. "
'이뤄진 기도와 체념된 소망은
얼마나 행복한가! '
I want to be
a great big, huge elephant...
난 거대한 코끼리가
되고 싶어
with a huge trunk like that.
저런 큰 코를 가진
코끼리!
Clem? Clementi ne?
클레멘타인?
I haven't heard that one.
I t's lovely.
- 처음 듣는데 참 아름답군
- 지금 적절할 거 같았어요
I just thought it would
be appropriate, maybe.
I really admire
the workyou do, Howard.
선생님 하시는 일
높이 사요
I don't mean to be so familiar.
Oh, it's fine. It's fine.
- 잘은 몰라도
- 좋은걸, 그 명언도
I-I-I-I-I--
I'm happy to hear--
죄송해요
[ Sighing ]
I've loved you
for a very long time.
오랫동안 사모해 왔어요
I shouldn't have said that.
Oh, Mary, no.
- 괜히 고백했나 봐
- 넌 정말 근사한 아가씨야
It's-- You're a wonderful girl.
But I-- You know,
I have a wife and kids.
하지만 내겐
아내와 애들이 있어
You know
I have a wife and kids.
Oh, Mary.
Oh, Mary, we can't do this.
우리 이래선 안 돼
Oh, whoa.
Well, good morning,
Mrs. Mierzwiak.
오셨어요, 사모님?
[ Honking ]
[Mary]
What?
Oh, myGod!
- 맙소사!
- 누군데요?
Who is it?
[ Sighs ]
Uh--
Thankyou, Stan.
Thanks a lot.
고마워서 눈물이 난다
Hollis. Hollis!
[Engine Starts ]
여보!
Hollis!
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Hollis.
잠깐만 서봐
- I knew it, Howard.
- Hollis, it didn't start out
to be like this.
- 이럴 줄 알았어
- 원래 일하러 왔어
I came here to work.
Hollis, this is a one-time mistake!
딱 한 번 실수한 거라고
I'm astupidgirl
with astupidcrush!
Yeah.
제가 선생님 좋아해서
유혹했어요
I swear I basically
forced him into it!
Don't be a monster, Howard.
Tell the girl.
잔인하게 굴지 말고 말해줘
Tell me what?
뭘 말해요?
딱해라
Oh, you poor kid.
You can have him.
네가 가져라
진작 그랬지만
You did.
What?
뭐요?
Oh, uh,
we have a history.
우린 좋아했었어
I'm sorry.
Y-You wanted the procedure.
미안해, 네가 원해서 지웠던 거야
You--
You wanted it done...
다 잊어버리고
새 출발하겠대서
so you could get past, uh--
You could-- Yeah.
Um, I have to, uh,
finish the work in there.
가서 마저 일해야 돼
좀 있으면 아침이라
It's almost morning.
나중에 얘기하자
괜찮겠지?
We'll talk later.
Okay?
[Stan ]
Hey.
매리
Let me giveyou a lift home.
집에 바래다줄게
Fuck this thing. Damn it.
이건 또 왜 이래
Hi.
- 안녕하세요
- 왔어요?
Didn't figureyou'd showyourface
around me again.
다신 못 볼 줄 알았는데
I guess I thought
you were... humiliated.
창피해하면서 도망쳤잖아요
You did run away,
after all.
Ijust neededtoseeya.
- 실은 할 말이 있어요
- 그래요?
Yeah?
내가...
데이트 신청해도 될까요?
I'd like to, um,
takeyou out or something.
You're married.
유부남이잖아
무슨 그런 소리를!
나 결혼 안 했어요
Notyet. Not married.
No, I'm not married, no.
Look, man,
I'm telling you right offthe bat
I'm high maintenance,
미리 말하는데
나 관리하려면 피곤해요
so I'm not gonna tiptoe
around your marriage...
당신 결혼했다고
조심하지도 않을 텐데
orwhatever it is
you've got going there.
- 그래도 좋다면 까짓 연애해요
- 좋아요
Ifyou wanna be with me,
you're with me.
Okay.
남자들은 내가 자신을
채워줄 거라 여기는데
Too many guys think I'm a concept,
or I complete them,
or I'm gonna make them alive.
But I'm just a fucked-up girl
who's looking for
my own peace of mind.
난 겨우 내 앞가림하는
이기적인 애니까
- 구속하려 들진 말아요
- 가슴 깊이 명심하죠
Don't assign meyours.
I remember that speech
reallywell.
I had you pegged, didn't I?
You had the whole
human race pegged.
- 잔소리가 심하죠?
- 고질병 수준인데
Hmm. Probably.
딱 맞췄네
I still thoughtyou were
gonna save my life,
날 구해줄 거란 생각은 변함없었어
even after that.
Mmm. I know.
알아
It would be different...
다시 해보면
분명 달라질 거야
ifwe could just give it
another go around.
Remember me.
날 잊지 말고 최선을 다 해봐
Tryyour best.
Maybe we can.
우린 할 수 있어
매리, 2002년 10월
[ Mierzwiak]
Okay, so just tell me
whatyou remember,
기억나는 걸 말하면
거기서 시작하지
and, uh, then we'll
take it from there.
[ Mary]
Okay.
알았어요
I liked you immediately.
처음 본 순간 좋아졌어요
You didn't
come on to me at all.
제게 시큰둥하니까
더 끌리더라고요
I liked that.
I was so tongue-tied
aroundyou at first.
제대로 말도 안 나왔지만
똑똑하게 보이고 싶었죠
I wantedyou to think
I was smart.
I couldn't wait
to come to work.
빨리 일하러 가서
당신 보고 싶었고
I had these fantasies
of us being married...
우리가 결혼해서
and having kids and... just--
아이 낳는 꿈도
Oh, Howie, I can't do this.
도저히 못하겠어요
[Mierzwiak ]
We agreed it's forthe best, Mary.
이게 최선이라고 여긴 거잖아
[Mary Crying]
Yeah, I know.
그건 알지만
어쩜 좋아!
Oh, God.
- 내가 밑을 받치면
- 됐어
I 'll take the bottom and you--
Uh-uh-uh! No, no, no. Here.
I can take that.
So you want me to carry that?
조엘, 받아 봐
당신은 아이스박스 들고
Help me with that.
Can you get the cooler?
Honey, the cooler is--
- 들 수 있어
- 가볍네
That's light, huh?
Oh, I can get that.
You can get it.
- 내가 들게
- 안 돼!
No, no, no, no!
Don't take anything.
I can take the plane.
- 그냥 몸만 가라
- 비행기 들게
Put the thing up.
Put the gate back up.
트렁크나 닫아
[Joel]
This is the daywe met.
우리가 만난 날이야
You were down bythe surf..
I couldjust makeyou out
in the distance.
넌 멀리 있었지만
저 여자다 싶었지
I remember being drawn to you
even then.
I thought, "Wow, how odd.
I'm drawn to someone's back. "
네게 막 끌리는데
기분이 묘하더라고
넌 오렌지색 추리닝 차림이었지
You were in that orange sweatshirt
that I would come to know so well...
이젠 너무 익숙하고
별로 안 좋아하지만
and even hate, eventually.
At the ti me I thought,
" How cool! An orange sweatshirt."
그땐 멋진 추리닝이라 생각했어
Hi there.
- 안녕하세요
- 네
Hi.
I saw you sitting over here...
여기 혼자 앉아있는 걸 보고는
너무나 고마웠죠
byyourself,
and I thought, "Thank God.
나처럼 적응 못하는
사람이 또 있구나!
Someone normal
who doesn't know how to interact
at these things either."
Yeah.
I don't ever know what to say.
말 주변이 없어서요
I'm Clementine.
클레멘타인이에요
Can I borrow a piece
ofyour chicken?
치킨 한 조각
빌릴 수 있을까요?
And then you just took it...
그리곤 대답할 새도 없이
바로 집어갔지
without waiting for an answer.
It was so intimate,
벌써 연인이 된 것처럼
허물없는 기분이었어
Iike we were already lovers.
I'm Joel.
- 조엘이에요
- 반가워요, 조엘
Hi,Joel.
So, no jokes about my name.
내 이름 갖고 놀리기 없기예요
You mean like--
♪ Oh, my darling, oh, my darling
Oh, my darling Clementine ♪
♪ 내 사랑아, 내 사랑아
♪ 나의 사랑 클레멘타인
Huckleberry Hound,
that sort ofthing?
이를테면 이렇게?
Yeah. Like that.
- 네, 그렇게요
- 안 놀릴게요
Oh, nojokes. Nojokes.
One ofmyfavorite things when I was a kid
was my Huckleberry Hound doll.
사실 어릴 적엔
'클레멘타인'만 불렀죠
Oh.
I thinkyour name is magical.
매혹적인 이름이에요
This is it,Joel.
이런 추억이 곧 사라지게 돼
It's gonna be gone soon.
I know.
- 알아
- 어떡하지?
What dowe do?
Enjoy it.
그냥 음미하자
- 결혼했어요?
- 아뇨
[ Clementine]
You married?
No.
우리 여기로 이사해요!
Let's move into
this neighborhood!
같이 사는 사람은 있어요
I do sort oflive
with someone though.
Male or female?
What?
- 남자, 여자?
- 네?
Female. Female.
당연히 여자죠
At least I'm not barking
up the wrong tree.
호모는 아닐 테니 안심 되네
You know these people?
No, of course not.
Come on.
- 아는 사람 집이에요?
- 당연히 아니죠
They might have a dog.
- 개라도 있으면?
- 그런 거 없어요
[ Giggling ]
There's no dog.
What areyou doing?
- 뭐해요?
- 밖은 춥잖아요
It's freezing out.
I can't believe this.
말도 안 돼
Hoo-hoo!
- Clementine!
- There we go. Whoo-hoo!
- 클레멘타인!
- 여기요
그러지 말고 들어와요
Come on, man.
The water's fine.
Nobody's coming here tonight.
Believe me.
이 밤에 누가 온다 그래요
It's dark.
엄청 어둡네
So, uh, what's
your girlfriend's name?
여자친구 이름이 뭐예요?
Naomi, but we're not really--
I mean--
나오미
근데 우리
We're--
[ Laughing ]
Whatever.
어쨌든 이거 멋지네요
So this is great.
Now I can look for, um,
candles, matches...
촛불에 성냥! 술도 찾을 테야
and the liquor cabinet.
Oh, God.
못 살아
[ Tapping Phone Receiver Button ]
I thi nk we should go.
- 나가죠
- 먹통이에요
There's no phone I i ne.
What?
- 네?
- 가자고요
I think we should go.
Why?
왜요?
오늘밤만은 우리 집인걸요
It's our house...
just for tonight.
[ Sighs ]
We are "David and Ruth Laskin."
우리가 데이빗과 루스예요
Which one doyou want to be?
Uh--
둘 중 누구 할래요?
난 굳이 와이프 안 해도 돼
I prefer to be Ruth,
but I can be flexible.
What areyou do--
[ Chuckling ]
뭐 찾아요?
Alcohol!
Oh, boy.
알코올! 음료수!
So, areyou okaywith wine?
- 와인 괜찮아요?
- 글쎄
I don't know.
Well, you choose the wine.
와인 골라봐요
난 가서 어울리는 옷 입고 올 테니
I'm gonna go find the bedroom
and slip into something more... Ruth.
I'm Ruth-less at the moment.
I reallyshouldgo.
- 그래야 분위기 살지
- 가야 돼요
[Wind Howling]
I've gotta catch my ride.
친구 차 타야 해요
- 그럼 가요
- 갔어
So go.
I did.
[Joel's Voice ]
I thought maybeyou were a nut,
넌 또라이 같았거든
butyou were exciting.
근데 끌리더라
[ Clementine ]
I wish you'd stayed.
- 가지 않길 바랬어
- 그러게
I wish I 'd stayed too.
Now I wish I 'd stayed.
I wish I 'd done a lot of things.
이제 와서 후회가 되네
Oh, God, I wish I had--
정말이지
I wish I'd stayed. I do.
가지 말 걸 그랬어
Well, I came back downstairs,
andyou were gone.
I walked out. I walked out the door.
- 내려와보니 가버렸더군
- 밖으로 나간 거야
Why?
I don't know.
I felt like a scared little kid.
- 왜?
- 글쎄, 물에 빠진 애처럼
I was like--
It was above my head.
I don't know.
- 겁에 질렸었어
- 겁이 났다고?
You were scared?
그래
나 그런 거 알잖아
Yeah.
Thought you knew that
about me.
[Joel's Voice ]
I ran back to the bonfire,
trying to outrun my humiliation, I think.
창피하면 피하기부터 하는 거
[ Clementine ]
Was it something I said?
Yeah.
- 내가 그랬니?
- 응
You said, "So go"...
그럼 가라고
경멸적인 투로 말했어
with such disdain, you know?
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
- 미안해
- 괜찮아
Joely?
이번엔 가지 마라
What ifyou stayed this time?
I walked out the door.
이미 나와서
아무 기억도 없어
There's no memory left.
Come back and make up
a good-bye, at least.
그럼 작별인사라도 해
좋은 추억 나눈 듯
Let's pretend we had one.
Bye,Joel.
잘 가, 조엘
[Joel ]
I loveyou.
사랑해
[ Whispering ]
Meet me in Montauk.
몬타우크에서... 만나자
[Rob ] I didn't crash the plane.
The plane crashed.
I didn't crash the plane.
비행기가 저절로
추락해버린 거야
[ Carrie ] You were operating the plane
with the remote control,
and then it crashed.
자기가 리모컨으로 조종했잖아
[ Rob ]
It was fucking windy.
Come on, man.
- 바람이 너무 불었어
- 대마초 피우고 운전하다니!
[ Carrie ]
You're stoned, andyou're driving.
술 깨는 효과가 있대
그래서 술 마시면 꼭 피우지
[ Rob ]
Yeah, the pot balances it out.
The pot brings you back up.
That's why I smoke it.
IfI'm going to be drinking,
then I'll smoke it.
It does.
That's a medical fact.
의학적으로도 증명된 거야
It was proven
on the Science Network.
- 앞이나 잘 봐
- 아무것도 안 보여
[ Carrie ]
Honey,just watch the road.
[ Rob ] I can 't see shit.
예쁜 여자와 얘기하던데
I saw you tal ki ng
to somebody pretty.
She was nice.
Yeah, man. Who was that?
- 착하더라
- 누군데?
She was, um, just a girl.
그냥... 어떤 아가씨야
[ Beep ]
Okay.
다 됐군
[ Groans ]
[ Line Ringing ]
[Ringing Continues ]
So I gotta--
I gotta drop the van off.
- 차 갖다 놓을게요
- 고맙네
Thanks, Stan. Thanks.
We'll talk.
[Horn Honks ]
나중에 보세
[ Van Door Closes,
Engine Starts ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Sighs ]
Hey!
매리!
Hey.
매리
You got a lot
ofyour stuff there, I see.
Yeah, that's right. My stuff.
- 네 물건이잖아
- 맞아
I take ityou're not coming back.
I wouldn't come back ifl wasyou either.
나 같아도 떠나
Do you swearyou didn't know?
I-I swear.
- 정말 몰랐어?
- 맹세해
So you didn't do the erasing?
Of course not. God, no.
- 네가 지운 게 아냐?
- 당연히 아냐
전혀 의심도 안 했어?
And you never even suspected
we were together?
[ Sighs, Clears Throat ]
Once, maybe.
한 번쯤은
I was coming back from a job,
and you were at his car.
일 마치고 와보니 차에서
둘이 얘기하고 있길래
I saw you two talking.
So I waved to you,
and you giggled, you know.
손 흔들었는데 웃고 있더라
어때 보였어?
How'd I look?
You looked happy.
행복해 보였어
비밀스러운 행복이랄까
Happywith a secret.
And after that?
- 그 후엔?
- 그렇게 같이 있는 건 본 적 없어
I never saw you two together
again like that, so I just--
그래서 내가 오버했나 싶었지
I don't know. I just figured
I was imagining things.
[Man On P.A., Indistinct]
몬타우크행 기차는
플랫폼 B에서 출발합니다
지금 곧 출발할 예정이오니
몬타우크로 가실 손님은
탑승해주세요
Aah!
[Man On P.A. ] Montauk train
now boarding on track "B. "All aboard.
I really like you, Mary Svevo.
나 진심으로 널 좋아해
그거 알아?
You know that?
고마워
Thanks.
Let me get my toothbrush.
칫솔 갖고 올게요
Yeah.J ust--
[ Beeps ]
[Patrick On Tape ]
Where areyou, Clem?
I'm worried.
어디 갔어?
걱정돼 죽겠잖아
La-la-la-la-la.
I feel likeyou're madat me,
and I don't know what I did.
나한테 화난 거 같은데
영문을 모르겠어
What did I do?
I love you so much.
널 많이 사랑해
네가 행복하다면 뭐든 해
I'll do anything
to make you happy.
바라는 대로 다 한다고
Tell me whatyou want me to do,
and I'll do it.
Listen, I'm gonna stop by this morning
just to make sure you're okay.
괜찮은지 궁금하니까
아침에 들를게
Oh. Whew.
Vamonos, senor.
[ Chuckles ]
출발하시죠!
I -I had a real ly nice time
last night.
- 어젯밤엔 정말 좋았어요
- 겨우?
Nice?
그렇게 열라 행복하긴
귀 빠지고 처음이에요
I had the best fucking night
of my entire fucking life...
Iast night.
그쯤 돼야지
That's better.
This is weird.
[Mary's Voice ] To allpatients
ofDr. Howard Mierzwiak.
이상하네
하워드 박사의 모든 환자분께
전 매리인데
절 기억 못 하실 거예요
Myname is MarySvevo.
"We've met,
but you don't remember me.
기억 지우려고 찾아온
회사에 근무하거든요
[ Mary's Voice Overlapping ]
I worked for a companyyou hired
to have part ofyour memory erased."
- 너무 끔찍한 일이라
- 광고지야?
I have since decided
that this is a horrible--
Some kind of teaser ad or something.
[Mary]
In orderto correct this,
I'm sending everyone's file back to them.
여러분의 파일을 돌려 드립니다
[ On Tape ]
My name is Clementine Kruczynski.
전 클레멘타인인데
조엘의 기억을 지울래요
I'm here to erase Joel Barish.
What is this?
I don't know.
- 뭐죠?
- 몰라요
He's boring.
Is that enough reason
to erase someone?
너무 따분한 것도
지우는 이유가 되나요?
I've been thinking lately
how I was before and how I am now,
그 사람 때문에
제가 많이 변했어요
and it's like he changed me.
그 사람하고 같이 있으면
제 자신이 싫어져요
I feel like I'm always pissy now.
I don't like myselfwhen I'm with him.
I don't like myselfanymore.
I can't stand to even look at him.
That pathetic, wimpy, apologetic smile.
보는 것조차 힘들어요
가소롭고 비굴한 미소라니
- That sort ofwounded puppy shit
he does, you know?
- What are you doi ng?
- 뭐해요?
- 아무것도
I 'm not doi ng anythi ng.
The bloom is certainly
fucking offthe rose at this point.
- 완전 시들해졌어요
- 나 갖고 놀아요?
- Are you screwing with me?
- No!
- 천만에!
- 갖고 노는 거잖아요
- You are screwing with me.
-Joel, I'm not!
- 그런 거 아녜요
- 아니면?!
- You clearly are.
- Look, let's just take a minute and--
우선 진정부터 하고
[ExasperatedSigh ]
[DoorCloses ]
[ Panting ]
Patrick, get the fuck away.
그냥 가라
꺼지란 말 안 들려?
Oh, sweetheart--
Get the fuck away from me!
Can we talk about it?
No! Get the fuck away!
- 얘기 좀 할래?
- 꺼지란 말이야!
[ Sobbing ]
[Sets Brake ]
Joel Barish.
- 조엘 배리스
- 클레멘타인
Hey, Clementine.
Hey.
- 안녕하세요
- 오랜만이네요
Nice to see you. Yeah.
Yeah.
[Joel On Tape ]
Really very educated.
똑똑하긴 한데
교양있진 않아요
I mean, she's smart, I think,
but not educated.
I couldn't really talk to her
about books, you know?
책보단 잡지를
많이 보는 거 같고요
She's more of
a magazi ne-readi ng girl.
Her vocabulary leaves
something to be desired.
어휘도 좀 딸리고
Sometimes--
I was embarrassed in public...
- 솔직히 창피했던 적도 있어요
- 안녕
Hi.
because she would pronounce...
'도서관'을 '도서방'이라잖아요
Iibrary "libary. "
Hi.
- 안녕
- 참나, '도서방'이라니
Libary. Libary.
Look what I found.
이걸 찾았어요
[ On Tape ] I think ifthere's
a truly seductive quality
about Clementine,
클레멘타인의 매력이라면
사람을 빠져들게 하는
묘한 매력이에요
it's that her personalitypromises
to take you out ofthe mundane.
You made me look skinny.
되게 날씬하게 그렸네
Amazing, burning meteorite...
별똥별을 보는 듯
마냥 신기하지만
will carryyou to another world
where things are exciting.
But what you quickly learn
is that...
이내 각본에 짜여진
여우 짓이란 걸 깨닫죠
it's really an elaborate ruse.
I ' m sorry I yel led at you.
- 소리 질러서 미안해요
- 괜찮아요
I t's okay.
So flashy
in a kind ofobvious way.
속이 뻔하게 비치죠
But still, it seduces you.
J oel, I real ly I i ke you.
나 그쪽 좋아하는데
나쁜 말해서 속상했어요
I hate that I said
mean things about you.
- Let me turn this off, okay?
- Hey, it's-- it's onlyfair.
- 그만 끌게요
- 나도 들어야 공평하죠
Where's the real Clementine?
머리 갖고 장난치는 건
더 한심해요
I mean, the whole thing with the hair--
it's all bullshit.
- I real ly I i ke your hai r.
- Thank you.
- 머리 맘에 들어요
- 고마워요
I really like your hair.
Thank you.
- 정말 좋아해요
- 고마워요
- 진짜예요
- 머리 색을 그렇게 자주 바꾸면
I do.
The world's a goddamn mess.
Is it some kind ofa revolt?
Change your hair color.
You want a drink or something?
- 한 잔 할래요?
- 위스키 있어요?
Do you have any whiskey?
No, I don't think hersex
is... motivated.
섹스도 별 생각 없이
하는 거 같아요
I saw it clearly
the last night we were together.
함께 한 마지막 밤도
섹시한 분위기는 아니었거든요
It wasn't sex.
It wasjust sad.
다만 슬펐죠
Hey. Sorry.
I thought there was more.
이거 밖엔 없네요
The only way Clem thinks
she can get people to like her...
자고 나야 자길 좋아한다고
여기나 봐요
is to fuck 'em...
or at least dangle the possibility
ofgetting fucked in front of'em.
언제든 잘 수 있단 걸
은근히 드러내죠
절망적이고 위태해 보이는 게
And she's so desperate
and insecure...
that she'll, sooner or later,
go around fucking everybody.
언제 누구와든
자버릴 거 같아요
- 나 안 그래요
- 저도 아니라고 생각해요
I don't do that.
I wouldn't think that
aboutyou.
- Because I don't.
- I know.
- 진짜 아니에요
- 알아요
Because it really hurts me
thatyou said that
because I don't do that.
- 지금 너무 속상해요
- 미안해요
I'm so sorry.
I 'm sorry about all this.
I 'm gonna... go.
나야말로 미안해요
그만 가볼게요
I 'm a little confused.
I don't really think I can be here.
너무 혼란스러워서
더는 못 있겠어요
Um... bye.
- 잘 있어요
- 잘 가요
Bye.
[ On Tape ]
I thought I knew herso well.
It was nice meeting you and all.
But I don't knowherat all.
만나서 반가웠어요
What a loss to spend
that much time with someone,
그리 오랜 시간을 함께 했는데
only to find out
that she's a stranger.
낯설어질 때의 당황스러움이란
Wait.
잠깐!
What?
I don't know.
- 왜요?
- 그냥 보내면 안 될 거 같아
J ust wait. J ust wait.
What do you want,Joel?
조금만... 기다려줘요
I don't know.
I want you to wait for...
just a while.
[ Quiet Sob ]
Okay.
Really?
- 그러죠
- 정말?
I'm not a concept,Joel.
I'mjust a fucked-up girl who's looking
for my own peace ofmind.
난 겨우 내 앞가림하는
이기적인 애예요
- I 'm not perfect.
- I can't see anything
that I don't like about you.
- 완벽하지도 않고
- 지금 그쪽 모든 게 맘에 들어요
Right now I can't.
But you will.
지금이야 그렇죠
You know, you will think ofthings,
and I'll get bored with you
and feel trapped...
근데 곧 거슬려 할 테고
난 자기를 지루해할 거야
because that's what happens
with me.
Okay.
괜찮아요
[ Crying ]
Okay.
- 뭐 어때
- 괜찮아요
[ Laughing ]
♪ Changeyourheart♪
♪ 마음을 바꿔봐요
♪ Look aroundyou♪
♪ 주위를 둘러봐요
♪ 마음을 바꾸세요
♪ Changeyourheart♪
♪ It will astoundyou♪
♪ 놀라게 될 거예요
♪ Now, I needyourlovin'♪
♪ 따뜻한 햇살처럼
♪ Like the sunshine ♪
♪ 당신의 사랑이 필요해요
♪ 모두들 언젠가는 배워요
♪ And everybody's
gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn
sometime ♪
♪ 모두들 언젠가는 배워요
♪ Everybody's
gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 모두들 언젠가는 배워요
♪ Mm-mm-mm ♪
♪ Change your heart ♪
♪ 마음을 바꿔봐요
♪ And look aroundyou ♪
♪ 주위를 둘러봐요
♪ Change your heart ♪
♪ 마음을 바꾸세요
♪ It will astoundyou ♪
♪ 놀라게 될 거예요
♪ I needyour lovin'♪
♪ 따뜻한 햇살처럼
♪ Like the sunshine ♪
♪ 당신의 사랑이 필요해요
♪ And everybody's
gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 모두들 언젠가는 배워요
♪ Everybody's gotta learn
sometime ♪
♪ 모두들 언젠가는 배워요
♪ Everybody's
gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 모두들 언젠가는 배워요
♪ Mm-mm-mm ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn
sometime ♪
♪ 모두들 언젠가는 배워요
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ Mm-mm-mm ♪♪